W
We
We A
We Ar
We Are
We Are F
We Are Fa
We Are Fam
We Are Fami
We Are Famil
We Are Family
Team WAF
Sub2smi by 블랙이글
프레스티지
잘 보고 계십니까?
Are you watching closely?
마술은 3단계로
이뤄집니다
Every magic trick
consists of three parts or acts.
1단계는 '평범한 마술'
The first part is called the Pledge.
마술사가 뭔가를
보여주죠
The magician shows you
something ordinary...
카드나 새,
혹은 사람을요
...a deck of cards, a bird, or a man.
그런 다음엔
He shows you this object...
관객을 무대로 불러내
...perhaps he asks you to inspect it...
확인을 시킵니다
... to see that it is, indeed, real.
조작이 아님을
보여주는 거죠
Yeah, unaltered, normal.
물론, 눈속임이에요
But of course, it probably isn 't.
- 어딜 들어가?
- 난 단원이야!
-Where do you think you ' re going?
-I ' m part of the bloody act, you fool.
2단계는 '대전환'
The second act is called the Turn.
마술사가
평범한 걸 가지고
The magician takes
the ordinary something...
특별한 묘기를
선보입니다
...and makes it
do something extraordinary.
여러분은 비법을
알아채지 못해요
Now, you 're looking for the secret,
but you won 't find it...
사실, 알아내려고
하지도 않죠
...because, of course,
you 're not really looking.
알면 실망이니
You don 't really wanna know.
속기를 원하죠
You want to be fooled.
박수는 이릅니다
But you wouldn 't clap yet...
사라지게 하는 걸론
부족하니까요
...because making something disappear
isn 't enough.
다시 나타나도록
만들어야 합니다
You have to bring it back.
그래서 3단계가
존재하는 거죠
That's why every magic trick
has a third act.
가장 어려운 단계
The hardest part.
'프레스티지'라
불립니다
The part we call the Prestige.
프레스티지?
The Prestige. And did Robert Angier,
the Great Danton, your employer...
당신 고용주인
로버트 앤지어가
마지막 단계까지
갔습니까?
...get to that final part
of his trick that night?
- 아뇨, 문제가 있었죠
- 무슨?
-No, sir. Something went wrong.
-What went wrong?
무대 밑에서 보든을 보고
I saw someone
making their way below stage.
따라갔는데
I followed him.
앤지어가 죽는 걸
지켜보더군요
It was Borden,
watching Mr. Angier drown.
선생 하는 일이, 커터 씨?
Would you please describe
your occupation to the jury, Mr. Cutter?
장비 책임자요
I'm an ingenieur.
마술을 고안하고
장비들을 만들죠
I design illusions and construct the
apparatus necessary for performing them.
무대 밑에 있던
그 물탱크도
So, Mr. Cutter...
...was this water-filled tank
beneath the stage...
필요한 장비였소?
...part of Mr. Angier's illusion?
아뇨
No, no. It was--
다른 마술에 쓰곤
치웠는데
The tank was brought on for the first trick
and then taken off-stage.
보든이 다시
갖다놨을 겁니다
Borden must have placed it
under the trap door after the interval.
물탱크 크기는?
How Iarge was this tank?
흔히 쓰이는
2천리터짜리요
Oh, it's a normal tank for escape
underwater, about 4 or 500 gallons.
어떻게 안 들키고
How do you think Mr. Borden...
물탱크를 옮겼을까요?
...was able to move the tank under
the trap door without anyone noticing?
마술사잖소
He's a magician. Ask him.
앤지어 마술의 비법을
공개하시오
I ask again that this man explain
the mechanics of Mr. Angier's illusion.
순간 이동은
The Real Transported Man...
최고의 마술이오
...is one of the most sought-after illusions
in this business.
비법이 밝혀지면
가치가 없어져요
I have the right to sell it on.
If I reveal the method here,
then the trick is worthless.
그걸 모르고 어떻게
진실을 밝히겠소?
How can we know that the tank wasn't
some part of the trick that went wrong?
피고 목숨이 달린
사건이오
Mr. Cutter, I see your predicament...
...but AIfred Borden's Iife
hangs in the balance.
내게 개인적으로
밝힌다면
If you were prepared to disclose
the details to me in private...
판결에 반영하겠소
...I might be able to judge
their relevance to the case.
그건 괜찮겠소?
Might this be an acceptable compromise?
소지품을 맡기세요
I'm gonna have to ask you
to turn out your pockets.
소장님은
Not my idea, sir.
보든이 사라지는
마술을 이용해
The warden saw his show in Manchester
Iast year where he vanished into thin air.
탈출할 거라 믿지만
He's convinced he'II try and escape.
송장 신세 아니고선
I told him the only way
that Borden's gonna disappear...
여기서 못 나가요
...is if I Ieave him out there
with the other inmates.
족쇄 확인해
Check the Iocks.
2번!
Twice.
오웬스요
My name is Owens.
변호사죠
I'm a solicitor.
아마추어 마술사인
콜드로 경이...
I represent Lord Caldlow, an accomplished
amateur magician and historian--
얼마?
How much?
- 콜드로 경은...
- 얼마 내겠소?
-Lord Caldlow is interested--
-How much for my tricks?
5천 파운드
Five thousand pounds.
동료인 팔론과 얘기해요
Talk with Fallon, my ingenieur.
Money's for him.
벌써 했소
가장 중요한 비법은
Yes, I did.
He offered to sell me your tricks.
안 팔겠다더군요
순간 이동
AII except the most valuable one:
The Transported Man.
위대한 마술이니
나라도 그러겠소
Well, I wouldn't forgive myself
for selling my greatest trick.
딸을 위해서도?
Even for your daughter?
교수형 되면
딸을 돌봐줄 사람이
If the newspapers are right
and you are for the drop...
- 필요하잖소
- 팔론이 돌봐줄 거요
-...your daughter will need Iooking after.
-Fallon will take care of her.
당신만큼 과거가
불분명한 작자라
Bernard Fallon? A man with a past
almost as obscure as your own.
양육권을 박탈당했소
Courts motioned that the girl
be removed from his care.
고아원으로 보내지겠죠
No, the girl will be an orphan.
고아원이 여기보다
낫다 할 수 있소?
I know you're no stranger to the workhouse.
It's better than here?
자존심을 버리면 딸한테
I'm offering you a way
to wrap up your affairs with dignity.
미래가 생겨요
And I'm offering your daughter a future.
콜드로 경이
잘 키워주실 거요
As Lord Caldlow's ward,
she will want for nothing. Ever.
생각해봐요
Well, think it over.
신의의 표시로
전해주라고 하셨소
And Lord Caldlow would Iike you
to have this as a show of good faith.
관심 가질 거라며...
앤지어 일기요
He said it might be of interest.
This is Robert Angier's diary.
당신 마술을 터득한
시기도 담겨 있죠
Including the time he spent
in Colorado Iearning your trick.
터득 못했어
-He never Iearned my trick.
-Really?
그의 순간 이동 마술이
On his return from Colorado, he mounted
a version of The Transported Man...
당신보다 낫다고
신문에 났었잖소
...that the papers said
was better even than your original.
그의 마술을 원하면
무덤에서 파내
If you want Angier's secrets,
you go dig him up and ask him yourself.
직접 물어봐요
난 당신 마술을 원해요
I want your secret, Mr. Borden.
딸을 생각해요
Consider your daughter.
암호
수수께끼
A cipher. An enigma.
여정
해답을 찾기 위한 긴 여정
A search. A search for answers.
콜로라도가 내 여정의
끝일지라도
Even if Colorado
is the end of my journey...
보든 마술의 비법을 밝히려면
오랜 시간이 걸릴 것이다
...it'll take much longer to unravel
the rest of Borden 's secrets.
물론, 암호를 풀
단어가 있겠지만
See, the cipher in his notebook
is unlocked by a single word...
해독하고 생각을 읽어내려면
몇 달은 걸릴 거다
...but it will still take months to translate
his writing and to know his mind.
얼마가 걸리든
해내고 말겠어
Well, my passion is equal to the task.
앤지어 씨?
콜로라도에 잘 오셨습니다
Mr. Angier?
Welcome to Colorado Springs.
- 전기가 있군요
- 네
-The whole town has electricity.
-Yes, sir.
Well, quite a reception.
- 과분한 환대군요
- 첫 손님이시거든요
You're our first guest of the season,
Mr. Angier.
얼마나 계실 예정인지?
Your telegram didn't indicate
how Iong you'II be staying with us.
무기한!
For as Iong as it takes.
내일 산에 갈 건데
마차가 필요해요
I'II need a coach tomorrow
to take me up the mountain.
과학 실험 때문에
못 올라가요
Well, the peak is closed, sir,
for scientific experimentation.
알아요
그래서 온 거요
Yes, I know. That's why I'm here.
여기부턴
걸어가셔야 돼요
You'II have to walk the rest,
I'm afraid, sir.
'감전 주의'
당신네 기자란 작자들은
I'm amazed how many of you
newspaper writers can't read my sign.
글도 못 읽는군!
기대했던 환대는
아니군요
Not the welcome I was expecting.
당신을 알아
I know you.
그레이트 단톤!
You're the Great Danton.
I saw your show in London seven times.
런던에서 공연을
여러 번 봤소
관객들 주머니 속의
물건을 전부 맞췄죠
You guessed every object
the audience had in their pockets.
앨리요
I'm AIIey.
펜스는 미안해요
훼방꾼이 많아서
Sorry about the fence.
People interfere with our work.
- 테슬라는?
- 왜요?
-I've come to see Tesla.
-Why?
동료한테 기계를
만들어줬었는데
He made a machine
for a colleague of mine sometime ago.
- 만나게 해주겠소?
- 불가능해요
-Can you get me a meeting with him?
-Impossible, I'm afraid.
돈은 많소
I brought a Iot of money.
미안해요
I'm sorry, Mr. Angier.
도와줄 수가 없군요
I simply can't help you.
호텔에 있을 거요
무기한!
I'II be staying at the hotel. Indefinitely.
내가 뭘 들었죠?
Hey, what am I holding?
시계!
Your watch.
1897년 4월 3일
보든 일기
Borden's journal entry for April 3rd, 1897,
describes a show at the Orpheum Theater.
오프엄 극장 공연을 묘사
That was just days after he first met me.
날 만난 직후였다
우린 마술사
지망생들이었고
We were two young men
at the start of a great career.
마술이 삶의 전부로
Two young men devoted to an illusion.
누구도 해칠
의도는 없었다
Two young men
who never intended to hurt anyone.
이 예쁜 아가씨를 묶을
용감한 분?
Which of you brave souls is willing
to bind this Iovely young woman?
손목을 묶고
If you would tie her wrists.
다릴 묶어요
Bind her feet around the ankle.
발목을 동여매고
혹시 선원입니까?
Are either of you two gentlemen sailors?
- 아뇨
-No.
단단하게 묶으세요
I'm sure you can both tie a strong knot.
그 사람 마술은
너무 뻔하고 지루해
He's complacent,
he's predictable, he's boring.
성공한 마술사지만
I mean, Milton has gotten success,
whatever that means...
배짱이 없어
모험을 않잖아
...and now he's scared.
He won't take any risks at all.
매번 똑같은 마술로
I mean, he's squandering
the goodwill of the audience...
- 관객을 따분하게 해
- 다들 좋아하잖아
-...with tired, second-rate tricks.
-They're old favorites.
총알 잡기처럼
새로운 걸 해야지
Favorites? Give me something fresh.
He won't even try a bullet catch.
자살 행위야
A bullet catch is suicide.
관객이 진짜 총알을 넣으면
황천 직행야
AII it takes is some smart-ass volunteer
to put a button in the barrel.
- 사람 심어요
- 지금도 넘쳐
-Fine. Use a plant.
-You can't for every trick.
손해가 막심해
-There'd be no seats Ieft for the punters.
-No bullet catch.
내 말은
새롭고 기발한 걸
해보자는 거라구
Whatever. The point is that a real magician
tries to invent something new...
다른 마술사들은
머리만 긁적일!
...that other magicians
are gonna scratch their heads over.
그리곤 비법을 팔겠다?
And then you sell it to him
for a small fortune.
-AII right.
-Yeah.
그런 마술 개발했어?
I suppose you have such a trick.
- 그럼요
- 나한테 팔래?
-Actually, I do.
-Would you care to sell it to me?
딴 사람은 못해요
No.
No one else could do my trick.
금방 따라 할 거야
-Any trick can be duplicated, right?
-Wrong.
진짜 위대한 마술이면
If Mr. Borden
has invented his masterpiece...
본인만 할 수 있어야지
...it might be only he's prepared to do it.
밀톤은 연기자지
Milton is a great showman,
but Borden is right.
마술사가 아냐
He won't get his hands dirty.
진짜 마술을 보려면
텐리 극장으로 가봐
If you wanna see what it takes
to make real magic, go to the Tenley.
거기 중국인이
진짜 마술사지
There's a Chinaman there,
and he really has what it takes.
- 청링수
- 입장료 비싸요
-Chung Ling Soo.
-Pricey. I can't afford that.
표 받는 친구를 알아
I know the bloke on the door.
둘이 보고 와
You two go and see that show...
어항 마술 비법을
알아오면
...and whichever one of you
can tell me...
...how he does
the goldfish-bowl trick...
상을 주겠어
-...gets a prize.
-AII right.
- 뭔데요?
- 아크만 앞에서
-Which is?
-Ten minutes on-stage...
10분간 오디션!
...with my old friend Mr. Ackerman.
누군데요?
-Really?
-Who's Ackerman?
런던 최고의 극장 대리인
The top theatrical agent in London.
매듭이 느슨했어
I saw you drop the knot again.
- 손을 비틀었어요
- 아직도 몰라?
-I think I turned my wrist.
-Some nights, you just don't get it, do you?
줄이 느슨하면
다리가 부러질 수 있어
I mean, if that knot slips
and Julia's on the hoist, she'II break a Ieg.
그러니까 제 말처럼
이중 매듭으로 해요
It's the wrong knot. Like I said,
the Langford double will hold tighter.
절대 안돼
그건 너무 위험해
The Langford double isn't a wet knot.
It's too dangerous.
잘못했다간
줄리아가 죽어
If the rope swells up, she won't slip it.
- 문제없어요
- 연습하면 돼요
-I can slip a Langford underwater.
-She can slip it. We'II practice.
보든, 그만해
Hey, Borden, he said no.
매듭에 대해서
뭘 아는데?
Yeah, well, you know knots
better than me, do you?
실수는 안돼
Listen, no more mistakes.
앞으로 네가 묶을래?
AII right. Yeah, do you?
You wanna take over?
- 그만해
- 못하겠지
-Just Ieave it.
-I didn't think so.
저 친구, 어디서 왔죠?
-Hey, Cutter, where's he from?
-Where are you from?
그러는 자넨?
버질 조수야
-He shifts props for Virgil at the hall.
-Aren't you worried he'II steal your tricks?
당신 마술 훔치면?
- 그럴 일 없어
- 어떻게 알죠?
-He doesn't deal in methods.
-How do you know?
버질 마술 캐내라고
내가 심어놨거든
Because I hired him to find out
how Virgil does the orange trick.
- 믿음이 안 가요
- 타고난 마술사야
-Well, I don't trust him.
-He's a natural magician.
당연히 못 믿겠지
Of course you can't trust him.
괜찮은걸 뭐
I think he's all right.
- 남자라면 다 괜찮지
- 자기도!
-You think everyone's all right.
-Even you.
앞으로 조심해
아내 다리에 키스하는 걸
Watch your sightlines. If I can see you
kissing your wife's Ieg every night...
관객들이 보면 큰일나
...so can the blokes
at the ends of row three and four.
- 아냐, 틀렸어
- 틀림없어
-You're wrong. It can't be.
-No, it is.
보라구
-Look at the man.
-This is the trick.
저건 속임수야
전부 연기라구
This is a performance right here.
This is why no one can detect his method.
그래서 아무도
의심하질 않지
마술에 대한 헌신
Total devotion to his art.
완벽한 희생
Utter self-sacrifice, you know?
알겠어?
일상을 벗어나는
유일한 탈출구지
It's the only way to escape all this,
you know.
AII right.
물도 안 들었는데
못 들겠어
I can barely Iift this thing
and it's not even filled with water.
금붕어도 없고!
Or fish. Look.
전혀 모르겠어
잠깐만
I don't know. Hang on a second.
힘이 천하장산가 봐
He must be strong as an ox.
절름발이 행세를
해왔다고?
He's been pretending
to be a cripple for years.
사람들 앞에선 항상!
Any time he's in public. Any time
he goes out. It's unthinkable.
보든이 단번에 알아냈지
Borden saw it at once,
but I couldn't fathom it.
나라면 딴 사람처럼
살진 못해
Living my whole Iife
pretending to be someone else.
- 그렇게 살잖아
- 이름만 바꿨지
-You're pretending to be someone else.
-I don't think changing a name compares.
이름, 정체, 고향...
전부 숨기잖아
Not just your name.
Who you are and where you're from.
마술하는 걸
가족이 싫어하니까
I promised my family I wouldn't embarrass
them with my theatrical endeavors.
좋은 예명이 생각났어
I thought of a name for you.
그레이트 단톤
The Great Danton.
맘에 들어?
Do you Iike it?
- 세련됐잖아
- 불어 이름은 싫어
-But it's sophisticated.
-It's French.
보든은 암호로
비법을 숨겨놨다
Borden writes as if no one but he
understood the true nature of magic.
희생이 뭔지 알기나 해?
But what does he know of self-sacrifice?
멍청한 자식
You bloody fool.
새를 죽였어!
-He killed it.
-What?
왜 그래?
What's wrong?
- 죽였어요!
- 아냐
-He killed it.
-I'm sure he didn't.
다시 나타날 거야
See? Look, now
he'II bring it back.
진짜 죽였어요
No, he killed it.
아냐
No.
봤지? 멀쩡하잖아
안 죽었어
Look. See?
He's all right. He's fine.
-Look at him.
-But where's his brother?
또 한 마리는 어딨죠?
아드님이
아주 똑똑하군요
He's a sharp Iad, your son.
아뇨, 조카예요
Oh, he's my nephew.
오늘 운 좋았어
You're the Iucky one today.
잘 보고 있니?
Are you watching closely?
더 자세히 봐
Look closer.
아무한테도 보여주지 마
Never show anyone.
알려달라고 해도
They'II beg you and they'II flatter you for
the secret, but as soon as you give it up...
절대로 비법을
알려줘선 안돼
...you'II be nothing to them.
알았어?
절대!
You understand? Nothing.
중요한 건 비법이 아냐
The secret impresses no one.
어떻게 쓰는가,
그게 중요하지
The trick you use it for is everything.
- 점심 고마웠어요, 보든 씨
- 별말씀을
-Well, thank you for Iunch, Mr. Borden.
-You're welcome.
알프레드예요
-AIfred. It's AIfred.
-AIfred.
차 한잔 줄래요?
So I could use a cup of tea.
주인한테 들키면
큰일나요
I'd scandalize the Iandlord. I think not.
문 잠그면 내가
못 들어갈 거 같애요?
You think that's--?
Is that enough to keep me out?
네
I think so.
다음에 봐요
So I'II see you again?
우유와 설탕?
Milk and sugar?
- 뭐가 들었소?
- 앤지어 기계요
-What's in there?
-Angier's machine.
당신이 만들었소?
You built this, Mr. Cutter?
아뇨, 마술사가 아닌
Oh, no, sir.
This wasn't built by a magician.
마법사가 만들었죠
This was built by a wizard.
마술을 현실로
바꿀 수 있는 사람
A man who can actually do
what magicians pretend to do.
판사님, 이 장비들은
어떻게 되죠?
Tell me, Your Honor, what happens
with these things after the trial?
콜드로 경한테 팔렸소
They've been sold to a Lord Caldlow.
수집가인데
사건에 관심이 많아요
An avid collector,
apparently very interested in the case.
이건 팔지 마요
Yeah, well, don't Iet him take this.
- 이유는?
- 너무 위험해요
-Why ever not?
-It's too dangerous.
겉만 번지르르했지
간단한 속임수겠죠
I'm sure beneath its bells and whistles
it's got a simple and disappointing trick.
가장 실망스럽죠
Most disappointing of all, sir...
속임수가 아녜요
...it has no trick.
진짜죠
It's real.
앤지어가 익사한
물탱크요?
This is the tank Angier drowned in?
Yes.
여길 통해
This is the place where the performer's
hand reaches through to the trick padlock.
연기자가
가짜 자물쇠를 열죠
전형적인
탈출 묘기 장비군요
A standard magical apparatus
for escapes.
한 가지가 틀려요
Yeah, with one important difference:
가짜 자물쇠가 아녜요
This isn't a trick Iock.
누군가 바꿔놓은 거죠
It's been switched for a real one.
완전 범죄군
What a way to kill someone.
그들은 마술사예요
연기력이 뛰어나죠
They're magicians, Your Honor.
Showmen.
때와 장소를 안 가리고
Men who Iive by dressing up plain
and sometimes-brutal truths...
사람들을 놀라게 해요
...to amaze, to shock.
관객이 없어도?
Even without an audience?
있었어요
There was an audience.
이 탱크는
You see, this water tank...
그들한텐
특별한 의미가 있죠
...was of particular significance
to these two men.
끔찍하지만
특별한 의미요
Particularly awful significance.
이 예쁜 아가씨를 묶을
용감한 분?
Which of you brave souls is willing
to bind this Iovely young woman?
손목을 묶고
If you would tie her wrists.
발목을 묶어요
Bind her feet around the ankle.
혹시 선원입니까?
Are either of you two gentlemen sailors?
아뇨
No.
단단하게 묶으세요
I'm sure you can both tie a strong knot.
Robert!
No! No! No!
줄리아
Julia. Julia.
Julia! Julia!
한 선원을 알았네
I knew an old sailor once.
바다에 빠졌는데
옷이 돛에 걸렸지
He told me he went overboard,
tangled in the sails.
구조되고 5분 만에
깨어났는데
They pulled him out,
but it took him five minutes to cough.
그 생사의 순간이
고향처럼 편했대
He said it was Iike going home.
자넨 왜 왔어?
What do you want, Borden?
줄리아 일은 유감이야
I'm sorry for your Ioss, Angier.
어떤 매듭을 썼지?
Which knot did you tie?
나도 내 자신한테
물어봤어
I keep asking myself that.
- 근데?
- 그런데...
-And?
-And....
미안해
나도 모르겠어
I'm sorry, I just don't know.
몰라?
You don't know?
미안해
I'm sorry.
모른다구?
You don't know?
몰라?!
AIfred?
좋은 소식이야
공연이 잡혔어
Good news.
We got our first booking today.
- 누구시죠?
- 장비 담당 팔론
-I don't think we've had the pleasure.
-Mr. Fallon is my ingenieur.
- 어디서 났어?
- 애걸하고 빌리고 슬쩍 했지
-Where did you get all of--?
-Begged, borrowed, and don't ask.
수완이 뛰어난 친구야
He's a very enterprising soul,
is Mr. Fallon.
- 보수는?
- 벌면 돼
-So--
-We can't afford to pay him.
Money will come
when we get the audience.
그때까진?
내 수입으론 벅차
But what about until then? I mean,
what I earn, it's barely enough for us.
걱정 마
밥도 나눠 먹을게
Don't worry about it. I'II share
half my food with him or something.
나눠 먹을 사람은
따로 있는걸
You're already going to be doing that
with someone else.
당신 혹시...
-No. You're--?
-Having a baby.
아길 가졌어
맙소사
팔론한테 말할게
Oh, my God. We should have told Fallon.
우리 아기라니!
That is great. We're having a baby.
-We're having a baby.
-Oh, come here.
이건 뭐야?
AIfred, what's this?
아크만 관심을 끌
비장의 무기
Oh, this is just the trick to wake
Ackerman up at the end of my act.
당신이 말한
위대한 마술?
Is it the masterpiece? The great trick?
아니, 그건 멀었어
No, no, no. The world is not ready
for that one yet.
이건 아주 평범해
총알 잡기!
This is just your run-of-the-mill,
daring, spectacular bullet catch.
- 총알 잡기?
- 안전한 마술이야, 보여줄게
-A bullet catch?
-Yeah, but it's safe, I promise. Look.
- 나를 쏴
- 뭐?
-Shoot me.
-Shoot you?
쏴봐
Go on, shoot me.
- 여길 겨눠
- 난 못해
-Right there.
-No, I can't.
거기 말고 여길 쏴!
No, no, not there. Shoot me here. Don't--
- 어때?
- 굉장한걸
-How's that?
-That's very good.
- 어떻게 한 거야?
- 말 못해
-Go on, tell me how you do it.
-No, I can't do that.
- 그럼 이 마술 못해
- 못한다고?
-Well, then you can't do it. AIfred--
-I can't do it?
응, 혼자 자식 키울
자신 없거든
I'm sorry, AIfred,
but I can't raise a child on my own.
- 절대 비밀 지켜
- 알았어
-You don't tell anybody that I told you.
-Okay.
화약
Gunpowder...
헝겊
...wadding...
그리곤 총알
...and a bullet.
쇠꼬치
A ramrod.
손 내밀어봐
Hold out your hand.
화약만 터지지
총알은 없어
The bullet is not even in the gun
when the charge is fired.
방법을 아니까
정말 간단하다
Once you know,
it's actually very obvious.
하지만
Well, I mean, you still get--
위험하기도 해
죽을 수도 있고
It's dangerous. I mean,
people still get killed doing that.
어떻게?
-Well, how?
-Well, you know.
멍청한 관객이
진짜 총알을
Somebody could get a smart-ass.
He can put a penny or a button...
넣을 수도 있거든
...or may God forbid, Sarah,
somebody could put a bullet there.
걱정 마
Don't worry. Don't worry...
그런 일 없을 테니
걱정할 거 없어
...because I'm not gonna Iet
anything happen.
아무 일 없을 거야
Everything's gonna be all right...
난 당신을 끔찍이
사랑하니까!
...because I Iove you very much.
- 다시 말해봐
- 사랑해
-Say it again.
-I Iove you.
- 오늘은 아냐
- 뭐?
-Not today.
-What?
사랑한단 말,
오늘은 진심이 아냐
Well, on some days it's not true,
and today you don't mean it.
오늘은 나보다
마술을 더 사랑해
Maybe today you're more
in Iove with magic than me.
티가 나거든
I Iike being able to tell the difference.
진심으로 말할 땐
표정이 달라
It makes the days it is true
mean something.
그렇군
AII right.
쇠고리입니다
Metal rings, Iadies and gentlemen.
무례한 손님 여러분
If there are any
Iadies or gentlemen here.
- 아주 단단하죠
- 봤던 마술이야!
-Solid metal.
-Seen that already.
-Leave it out!
-Come on.
총!
총 묘기를 해!
Get out your gun, mate.
- 누가 던졌죠?
- 내가!
-Who threw that?
-I did!
Get out your gun.
You're gonna need it.
Get a gun.
이걸 보러 왔어요?
It's what you came for, is it?
누가 넣겠소?
So who wants to volunteer?
Me! Me!
Me.
Watch it, cowboy.
쏠 배짱 있어요?
Are you man enough, sir?
물론!
Yes.
어떤 매듭을 썼지?
Which knot did you tie, Borden?
어떤 매듭이었어?
나도 몰라
I don't know.
그는 해답을 원했고
난 진실을 말해줬다
He came in to demand an answer,
and I told him the truth.
사고가 있었던 밤,
내 자신과 싸웠다
That I have fought with myself
over that night.
나의 반쪽은
평범한 매듭을
One half of me swearing blind
that I tied a simple slipknot...
다른 반쪽은
이중 매듭이라 했다
...the other half convinced
that I tied the Langford double.
난 정말 모르겠다
I can never know for sure.
어떻게 모를 수 있어?!
How can he not know?
어떻게 몰라?
알고 있었을 거야
He must know what he did. He must.
틀림없어
새라, 아프잖아
Sarah, that bloody hurts.
왜 또 피가 나지?
I don't understand
how it can be bleeding again.
처음 다쳤을 때랑
똑같잖아
It's as bad as the day it happened.
- 의사 부를게
- 그럴 돈 없어!
-We have to get a doctor back.
-We can't afford the bloody doctor back.
- 애가 깼잖아
- 돌겠군
-You've woken her.
-Great.
빨리 손이 나아야
일을 다시 시작해
I'm sorry. I need this to heal
so I can go back to work.
이 손으로 어떻게
마술을 한다 그래?
AIfred, face things. What tricks
can you perform with this kind of injury?
카드 마술은 괜찮아
장치 사용하면 되고
I can do card pulls.
I can do some prop tricks.
또, 당신한테 말한
마술도 할 수 있어
I can still do that. And I can do the trick
that I've been telling you about.
나만이 가능한
위대한 마술!
The one that they're gonna
remember me for.
날 믿어
Come on.
술 마시고 깨달음을
얻을 줄은 몰랐네요
Never thought I'd find an answer
at the bottom of a glass.
많이 마셨군
Hasn't stopped you Iooking.
공연을 잡았어
Heard about a booking.
아담한 극장야
유능한 마술사한텐...
Nice Iittle theater.
Young up-and-coming magician.
- 누구 공연요?
- 자네!
-Who?
-You.
내 공연을?
왜요?
You got me a booking? Why?
입에 풀칠하려면
일거리 필요한데
I wanna keep on working.
줄리아 죽게 한 나를
And who's gonna hire the ingenieur
that killed Julia McCullough...
누가 쓰겠나?
...in front of a sellout crowd
at the Orpheum?
당신 잘못 아녔어요
Someone who knows
it wasn't your fault.
보든이 묶은
매듭 때문이죠
Someone who knows AIfred Borden
and his repertoire of exotic knots.
총알 잡기를 하다
다쳤다더군
I hear he had a spot of bad Iuck
catching a bullet south of the river.
위험한 마술이죠
That's a dangerous trick, that one.
창문을 가려서
We'II have to whitewash the windows...
관객들을
궁금하게 해야 돼
...confound the more curious members
of the public, but it will do.
- 조수가 필요해요
- 나한테 맡겨
-We should see about an assistant.
-I've made some arrangements.
예명은 정했나?
Have you settled on a name?
네
Yes, I have. The Great Danton.
그레이트 단톤
좀 구식이잖아?
It's a bit old-fashioned, isn't it?
아뇨, 세련됐죠
No, it's sophisticated.
피날레 묘기론
너무 진부해요
The birdcage can't be our climax.
Everybody knows it.
- 바꾸면 돼
- 죽이긴 싫어요
-Not Iike this they don't.
-I don't wanna kill doves.
그럼 그만둬
Then stay off the stage.
You're a magician, not a wizard.
자넨 마술사지
마법사가 아냐
손을 더럽혀야만
불가능을 성취해
You gotta get your hands dirty
if you're gonna achieve the impossible.
들어가
In here, Miss Wenscombe.
조수로 쓸만한지
테스트 해봐야지
No point in you meeting Mr. Angier
if you don't fit.
오른쪽에 서봐
On the right.
이게 다예요?
What's so hard about this?
아니, 저 밑으로
내려가야 돼
Nothing. But you're going down here.
잠깐만, 잠깐
이쪽으로 이렇게
Hold it. Hold it there.
This has gotta go around there.
- 이럼 안 보여요?
- 물론
-And this will conceal it?
-Yeah, oh, sure.
-AII right?
-Yeah.
단단히 조이고
-Now, take that one there.
-Yep. Okay.
- 밑을 고정해
- 위를 묶어요?
-Pin this under.
-And this ties up here?
앞쪽을
-That ties at the front.
-That's good.
최대한 숨을 참아
Breathe as Iittle as possible.
봤지?
이렇게 납작해져
Now, you see? That'II go. That'II flatten.
네
-I see. Yeah.
-Okay.
경험은 없지만
미모가 받쳐줘
She's not experienced,
but she knows how to present herself.
조수가 예쁠수록
시선이 분산되지
A pretty assistant is the most
effective form of misdirection.
감사합니다
Thank you.
마지막 마술입니다
Ladies and gentlemen,
for my final trick...
두 분만 나와주세요
...I will require the assistance
of two volunteers.
메릿 씨, 부탁해요
Mr. Merrit, if you would oblige me?
손을 여기로
Yeah. Okay. Bring your hand around.
밑에?
-Under?
-Under, yeah.
다리에 묶었어
There. I put it around its foot.
- 조심해요
- 괜찮아
-Careful.
-He's all right, ain't he?
지원자가 여기랑
-You get a volunteer to put a hand there.
-Yeah.
여길 잡게 해
And another one there.
새집 양쪽을 잡으세요
Mr. Merrit, if you'II place your hands
on either side of the cage, please.
고마워
Thank you, OIivia.
- 죽이진 않겠지?
- 그럼요
You best not be intending...
-...to hurt this animal, Mr. Angier.
-Of course not.
준비됐나?
You ready? AII right.
하나
One....
둘
Two....
셋
-Three.
-Three. Go.
시작!
정말 굉장해요
Well, that's bloody marvelous,
Cutter.
멋지군
Very nice.
무엇보다...
And the best part is....
피 묻힐 줄 알았어요
I thought you said
I had to get my hands dirty.
언젠간 그럴 거야
각오 있는지 봤지
Someday perhaps you will.
I just had to know that you can.
대단하군, 굉장해
-Very nice. Very nice, indeed.
-Thank you, Mr. Merrit.
선생의 멋진 극장에서
공연할 기회가 없었죠
I haven't had the chance
to compliment your beautiful theater.
관객이 가득 차면
더 멋질 걸세
Well, it'II be a Iot more beautiful
when it's full.
- 걱정 마세요
- 말은 그렇지
-Don't worry.
-Oh, you all say that.
손님 못 끌어들이면
딴 사람 쓸 거야
Why should I worry? If your tricks
don't get them in, somebody else's will.
총알 잡기나 수중 탈출
묘기를 부릴 사람으로
Maybe somebody willing to do
a bullet catch or a water escape?
잘못해서 사고 나면
Cheap thrills, Mr. Merrit.
People hoping for an accident,
Iikely to see one too.
극장 측에 좋을 거 없잖소
What would that do for your business?
- 일주일 주겠소
- 감사합니다!
-You got a week, John.
-Thank you, Mr. Merrit.
Thank you.
3번째줄 선생님?
Sir? In the third row there.
일어나서
손수건 보여주세요
PIease stand up
and show us your handkerchief.
내 께 아니오
This isn't mine.
앞줄 숙녀분 것과
바뀌었으니
Perhaps you'd be so good as to return it
to the Iady in the aisle.
다시 맞바꾸세요
I believe she has yours.
Thank you.
자꾸 실수해 미안해요
너무 긴장돼서요
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I'm making so many mistakes.
I'm so nervous.
관객 반응이 별로예요
The audience doesn't seem
to be responding.
봤던 마술이니까
이거면 달라질 거야
They've seen a Iot of tricks before,
but not this next one.
천을 덮어
Put a cloth over.
- 기도해줘요
- 샴페인 준비하지
-Fingers crossed.
-I'II have the champagne ready.
- 보신 적 있습니까?
- 다 봤어!
-You've seen this one before?
-We've seen them all.
더 어렵게 해보죠
I'II make it a Iittle harder then, shall I?
두 분만 나오셔서
새장을 들어주세요
Two volunteers, please. A Iady
and a gentleman to hold this cage with me.
세계 어디에서도
시도된 적 없는
I'II perform this feat in a manner
never before seen by yourselves...
새로운 방식입니다
...or any other audience
anywhere in the world.
부인, 양손으로
앞뒤를 잡으시고
Madam, if you'II place one hand on the back
of the cage, one hand on the front.
선생님은 위아래를
잡으세요
Sir, one hand on the bottom of the cage,
one hand on the top.
- 알아봤어야 했어요
- 정신 없었잖아
-Should have spotted him.
-You had a Iot of plates going.
다신 이 마술을
못하겠어요
-Don't suppose they'II Iet us do this again.
-No.
- 그럼 뭘로 피날레를 하죠?
- 공연? 끝났어!
-So, what's the climax of our show?
-Show? You don't have a show.
1주일 계약했잖아요
We have a week's engagement.
관객 손가락
자르라곤 안했어
To perform magic, not butcher birds
and break my customers' fingers.
장비들 치워
CIear out. Anything here
in the morning gets burned.
늦었어
-Mr. Merrit--
-It's done, John.
이미 코미디언을 고용했소
내키진 않지만!
I've hired a comedian.
You know I hate comedians.
극장은 많아
Well, there's plenty of good theaters.
새 마술 개발하고
예명을 바꾸자구
If we can come up with a new trick,
change the name of the act--
이름은 안돼요
The name stays.
그렇담 아주 기발한
마술이 필요하겠군
Right. Well, then the new trick's
gonna have to be irresistible, then.
두어 가지 있는데
I have a couple of methods to try out.
그걸 선보일
방법이 필요해
And then we need a new angle
on the presentation.
영감이 필요하면
Oh, and if you need some inspiration...
이번 주말에
과학 엑스포가 열려
...there's a technical exposition
at the AIbert Hall this week.
기술자, 과학자...
다 모여서
Engineers, scientists, you know?
대중들의 상상력을
발동시키지
That sort of thing
captures a public's imagination.
합석해도 되겠소?
비바람이 몰아쳐요
Mind if I join you? Tesla sends me
down here during the storms.
그레이트 단톤과
한잔 꺾을 기회죠
Perfect excuse to come join
the Great Danton for a drink.
여기 2잔
Two of them.
아름답죠?
뉴욕이 그립지만
Beautiful, isn't it, huh?
God, I miss New York though.
- 그럼 왜 여길?
- 번개가 잦고
-So why are you here?
-The Iightning Iives here.
훼방꾼들이 적어서
And not much else. Our work is secret.
암호요?
Is that a cipher?
일기인데 순서가
엉망으로 돼 있소
It's a rotating transposition
that shifts every day of the diary.
암호는 간단하지만
해독에 시간이 걸려요
Simple, but time-consuming to translate,
even when you have the five-Ietter keyword.
어느 부분이?
Which is?
동료 비법이라 말 못해요
We magicians have a circle of trust.
동료라면서
일기장을 훔쳐 왔다?
You have a circle of trust
with someone whose diary you stole?
샀다면?
Maybe I bought it.
비밀을 찾는군요
And you're hoping to find
a great secret in there.
벌써 찾았소
그래서 여길 왔죠
I've already found it.
That's why I'm here.
테슬라가
기계를 만들어줬소
Tesla built one for another magician.
- 왜 같은 걸?
- 라이벌 의식이죠
-Why would you want the same thing?
-Call it a professional rivalry.
몇몇 사람들한테
기계를 만들어줬지만
Mr. Tesla has built unusual machines
for unusual people.
일 얘긴 안 해요
But he would never talk about it.
난 그 기계만
입수하면 돼요
I understand discretion.
I just want the machine.
잔 비워요
Finish your drink.
보여줄 게 있소
I wanna show you something.
우리 실험을 보면
감탄할 거요
I think you'II have a special appreciation
for our work.
- 비밀이라더니?
- 당신은 마술사잖소
-I thought it was a secret.
-You're a magician.
누가 믿겠소?
Who's gonna believe you?
얼마 안됐소
Not Iong now.
우리 장비는
고압을 필요로 해요
Our equipment requires
a great deal of current.
발전기 쓰는 조건으로
마을에 전기를 깔았고
Tesla electrified the town in exchange
for using the generators when we need to.
사람들이 잘 때만
실험을 하죠
We do our tests
when the townspeople are asleep.
놀라면 안되니까
Mr. Tesla doesn't wanna scare anyone.
전선은 어딨소?
Where are the wires?
그거요
Exactly.
- 발전기는?
- 지난주에 봤잖소
-Where's the generator?
-You saw it Iast week.
- 10마일 거린데
- 15마일!
-That must be 1 0 miles from here.
-Fifteen.
내가 매일 다녀오죠
And I have to ride all of them
before I get to bed.
며칠 후에 연락하리다
I'II send word for you
in a few days, Mr. Angier.
마술
Magic. Real magic.
진짜 마술
세상을 깜짝 놀래킬
Now appearing only here
at London's Royal AIbert Hall.
온갖 신기술들이
최초로 선보입니다
One of the miracles of our age.
A technological marvel.
보고도 못 믿을
You've never seen anything Iike it
in your Iives.
놀라움을 만끽하십시오
Your eyes will not believe
what they're witnessing.
테슬라의 기적!
The miracle of Nikola Tesla,
Iadies and gentlemen.
공짜에 깨끗한 전기!
미래를 알고 싶으세요?
Free clean power.
Would you Iike to know the future?
세상이 바뀔 겁니다
The man speaking now
is going to change the world.
모두 들어오십시오
대기 시간도 없습니다
Ladies and gentlemen, come one, come all.
Immediate seating, no waiting.
테슬라 씨의
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm sorry...
기술 시현에 대한
...but objections have been raised...
안전 문제가
제기됐습니다
-...concerning the safety....
-They should be. Does that Iook safe to you?
테슬라 씨를
깎아내리려는
Part of Thomas Edison's
smear campaign...
토마스 에디슨의
모략입니다
...against Mr. Tesla's
superior alternating current.
그만하세요
Mr. AIIey, please.
테슬라 씨한테
We have asked Mr. Tesla
to reconsider...
재고를 요청했지만
-Which he will not.
-...his presentation.
어떠한 제한 사항도
거부하셨습니다
But I've been told he refuses
to appear under any such restrictions.
전부 나가요!
폭발할 거요!
CIear the hall!
This thing is gonna blow!
- 나가요!
- 여러분, 제발!
-CIear the hall!
-Ladies and gentlemen, please!
Where's the switch?
안전한 기계예요!
This is all perfectly safe.
안녕!
Hey.
Hello, you.
안녕, 제스
Hello, Jess.
오늘 엄마랑 재밌었어?
Have you had a nice day with Mummy?
사랑해
Sarah, I Iove you.
오늘은 진심이네
-See? Today it's true.
-Yeah.
Hello.
행복을 봤다
I saw happiness.
내가 누렸어야 할
행복을!
Happiness that should have been mine.
하지만 아녔다
But I was wrong.
그는 내가 질시한 삶을
살지 않았다
His notebook reveals
that he never had the life that I envied.
가족과의 행복을
즐기다가도
The family life
that he craves one minute...
혼자만의 자유를
갈구했던 것이다
...he rails against the next,
demanding freedom.
그의 정신은
분열돼 있었으며
His mind....
His mind is a divided one.
영혼은 불안했다
His soul is restless.
가족은 그의 변덕에
고통스러워했다
His wife and child tormented
by his fickle and contradictory nature.
뭐라고 부를 거야?
What do you think?
What do you think you'II call her?
몰라
I don't know.
이름이 있어야지
Everybody needs a name.
So, what's hers?
새라로 할래
Maybe Sarah.
예쁘다
예쁜 이름이야
That's a Iovely name.
오늘 뭐 하고 싶은지
얘기해봐
You talk about what you wanna do
for the rest of the day.
어서, 얘기해봐
AII right? Go on. You talk with her.
시설로 보낸대?
They're taking her away?
고아원에?
To the workhouse?
계속 얘기해
Now, you keep talking.
오웬스한테
마음 바꿨다고 해, 받아
Tell Owens I've reconsidered.
Take it. Go on, take it.
이게 최선이야
It's for the best.
이리 줘봐
Let me see.
- 당신 비법을 다 배우겠군
- 까막눈 아녔나?
-I'm gonna Iearn all the Professor's secrets.
-Only if I teach you how to read.
전부 눈속임이지?
They're just stupid tricks, right?
마술로도 여기선
못 도망쳐?
Haven't helped you
get out of here, have they?
진짜 자물쇠는
못 여시나?
Or can't you undo real Iocks, Professor?
때를 기다린다면?
Well, maybe I'm just biding my time.
어느 날 손을 내밀면서
당신한테 묻는 거지
Maybe one day I'II open my hand,
get your attention, ask:
"잘 보고 있어?"
"Are you watching closely? "
주문을 외곤
Maybe a magic word or two.
사라지는 거지
And then I'II be gone.
그 실력으로
어떻게 유명해졌지?
How'd you get so famous, then, eh?
마법!
Magic.
보든, 이리 와!
Borden, get back here!
고맙군!
Thank you.
닥쳐!
잡아!
Shut up! Get him down!
물러서!
Thank you.
열쇠 가져와!
Who's got a bloody key?
1899년 2월 8일
February 8th, 1899.
마침내 성과가 있었다
Today, finally a breakthrough.
테슬라와 만나기로 했다
Tesla 's agreed to see me.
안전해요
It's perfectly safe.
당신이
그레이트 단톤이군
So this is the Great Danton.
앨리한테
귀가 따갑게 들었소
Mr. AIIey has effused about your act to me
on any number of occasions.
다른 손 내밀어요
Hold out other hand.
전도체가 뭐죠?
What's conducting the electricity?
우리의 몸은
에너지를 전도하고
Our bodies, Mr. Angier,
are quite capable of conducting...
생성할 수 있소
...and, indeed, producing energy.
식사는 했소?
Have you eaten, Mr. Angier?
불가능한 게 필요합니다
I need something impossible.
혹시 들어봤소?
"불가능에 도전하라"
You are familiar with the phrase,
"Man's reach exceeds his grasp"?
거짓이오
It's a Iie.
마음만 먹으면
불가능은 없죠
Man's grasp exceeds his nerve.
세상은 급격한 변화를
원치 않아요
Society only tolerates
one change at a time.
처음 세상을
바꾸려 하자 모두가
The first time
I tried to change the world...
날 선각자라 했소
...I was hailed as a visionary.
두번째는
Second time,
I was asked politely to retire.
은퇴 압력을 받았죠
그래서 여기서
쉬고 있는 거요
So here I am, enjoying my retirement.
불가능한 건 없소
Nothing is impossible, Mr. Angier.
비쌀 뿐이지
What you want is simply expensive.
그 기계를 만들어주면
If I were to build for you this machine...
마술에만 쓰겠소?
...you would be presenting it
merely as illusion?
사람들이 마술을
진짜라 믿는다면
Well, if people actually believed
the things I did on-stage...
박수가 아니라
비명을 지르겠죠
...they wouldn't clap, they'd scream.
I mean, think of sawing a woman in half.
여잘 토막 내니...
비용에 대해서
생각해봤소?
Mr. Angier, have you considered
the cost of such a machine?
돈은 상관없어요
Price is not an object.
그것이 가져올 결과는?
Perhaps not,
but have you considered the cost?
무슨 뜻이죠?
I'm not sure I follow.
돌아가시오
Go home. Forget this thing.
집착을 버려요
I can recognize an obsession.
좋을 게 없소
No good will come of it.
선생의 집착은?
Hasn't good come of your obsessions?
처음엔 좋았지만
정도가 지나쳤죠
At first.
But I have followed them too Iong.
집착의 노예가 돼
결국 파멸할 거요
I am their slave, and one day,
they will choose to destroy me.
포기 않을 거란 거
아시잖습니까
If you understand an obsession,
then you know you won't change my mind.
그럼 좋소
So be it.
만들어줄 겁니까?
Will you build it?
벌써 만들기 시작했소
I have already begun to build it,
Mr. Angier.
신선한 공기를 즐겨요
I hope you enjoy the mountain air.
시간이 좀 걸릴 테니
This will take some time.
'죽음을 거부한 교수'
'순간 이동 마술로
돌아오다'
떠난 줄 알았는데?
I thought you'd gone.
갈 데가 없어요
I don't really have anywhere to go.
여기서 지냈어?
You've been sleeping here?
커터가 허락했어요
뭐 해요?
Cutter said it would be all right till we get
another booking. What are you doing?
연구!
Research.
라이벌 마술사의
비법을 알아내는 게...
Part of a magician's job is to watch
his competition, to see what illusions--
그 사람한테
복수할 거죠?
You're going to do something
to that man, aren't you?
커터는 둘이 서로
Cutter's hoping you'II Iet things Iie.
비긴 걸로 치고...
He says if Borden thinks things
are even between you two--
비겨?
Even?
아내랑 손가락이?
My wife for a couple of his fingers?
그에겐 가족이 있고
공연을 해
He has a family now, right?
And he's performing again.
별일 없었다는 듯
자기 삶을 산다고
Borden is Iiving his Iife just as he always
intended, as if nothing had happened.
난 어떻지?
And Iook at-- Look at me, all right?
- 혼자고 극장에선 쫓겨났어
- 내가 있잖아요
-I'm alone and no theater will touch me.
-Us.
변장하려면 제대로 해요
You're going to need a better disguise.
지원자 없어요?
Need a volunteer.
어떻게 됐어요?
What happened?
해쳤어요?
Did you hurt him?
말해봐요
What happened, Robert?
선생님
You, sir.
고무공이 맞죠?
Just a rubber ball, yes? Thank you.
보통 고무공이 아닙니다
Just a rubber ball, no.
아주 특별한 공이죠
Not normal. Not a normal rubber ball.
마법이죠
It's magic.
새로운 마술이었어
He had a new trick.
좋았어요?
Was it good?
최고의 마술이었지
It was the greatest magic trick
I've ever seen.
관객들 반응은?
Did they applaud when you saw it?
너무나 간단해서
The trick was too good,
it was too simple.
- 관객들은 놓쳤어
- 굉장했어요
-The audience hardly had time to see it.
-He's a dreadful magician.
아니, 끔찍한 연기지
No, he's a wonderful magician.
He's a dreadful showman.
상술을 전혀 몰라
He doesn't know how to dress it up,
how to sell--
- 어떻게 한 거죠?
- 대역을 써
-How does he do it?
-Uses a double.
아뇨, 그렇게
간단할 리 없어요
No, no, no, it's too simple.
This is a complex illusion.
방법을 모르니
복잡해 보이지
You only say that
because you don't know the method.
대역 없인 불가능해
It's a double at the end.
It's the only way.
3번 봤는데
모두 같은 자였어요
I've seen him perform the trick
three times now.
-The Prestige is the same man.
-No, it's not.
아냐
똑같은 자라구요!
The same man comes out
of that second cabinet.
맞아요
It's the same man.
장갑을 꼈지만
손가락 잘린 게
He wears padded gloves
to hide his damaged fingers...
표시가 나요
...but if you Iook closely you can tell.
나도 할 수 있어요
He doesn't know how to sell it
to an audience, but I do.
피날레 공연으로
딱이겠어
Yeah, well, we can use it
as a climax to the show.
Yes.
내 삶을 훔쳐갔으니
난 마술을 훔치겠어
The man stole my Iife,
I'm gonna steal his trick.
- 대역이 필요해
- 대역이 아녜요
-We gotta find someone who Iooks Iike you.
-He doesn't use a double.
보든이 어떻게
하는진 모르지만
Robert, I don't know
how Borden does the trick, so either--
그가 은퇴하면
비법을 사던가
You either wait for him to retire
and buy the secret...
아님 내 말대로 해
...or you Iisten to how I would do it.
똑같이 생긴 대역을
찾는 게 유일한 방법야
And the only way that I know how to do it
is to find you a bloody good double.
좋아요
AII right.
나랑 똑같이 생긴
사람을 찾아요
Take a good Iook.
Let's get out there and find me.
여길 봐
Look. Look.
뭐지?
What's that?
이건...
That is for you.
- 당신 꺼야
- 뭔데?
What's this for?
이리 와
Come here.
- 지난주엔...
- 그땐 기분 별로였어
-I asked you Iast week. You said you--
-You caught me in a wrong mood.
그치만 그땐...
But you went over all the--
새라, 내가 변덕이
좀 심하잖아
Sarah, I'm allowed to change my mind,
aren't I?
공연이 인기가 높아
The act is taking off,
soon we'II be in a bigger theater.
이젠 고생길 끝났어
Things will work out.
믿기질 않아
I can't believe it. Thank you.
고마워
너무 멋져!
Thank you. It's beautiful.
제리?
Gerry?
이게 누구야!
Darling, Iook at you.
제리 루트예요
Mr. Cutter, Mr. Angier,
I'd Iike you to meet Gerald Root.
안녕하시오
만나서 반갑소
A pleasure.
PIeasure to meet you fine gentlemen.
조크 말해줄까요?
가까이 와요
Would you Iike for me
to tell you a Iittle joke? Come here.
어때?
There we are. Yes?
웃기지 않소?
Are you Iaughing now?
물 좀 빼고 오겠소
Oh, dear, I have to take a piss.
- 미쳤어!
- 퇴물 배우예요
-He's out of his mind.
-Of course. He's an out-of-work actor.
완벽해
He's perfect. He needs a Iittle help...
좀 다듬으면
쌍둥이 같겠어
...but when I get done with him,
he could be your brother.
쌍둥이가 아니라
내가 돼야죠
I don't need him to be my brother,
I need him to be me.
한달이면 돼
Give me a month.
- 들어와
- 이쪽으로
Come around.
당신이 문을 열고
그리곤...
So you open the door and....
이리 와
Come on.
너무 딱딱해요
잘 것도 아니잖아
-Couldn't you have found a softer one?
-Well, it's not for sleeping on.
당신이 떨어지면
So if you come down through there...
루트가 저기로 올라가요?
-...does Root go up through there?
-Yep.
감쪽같을 거예요
It's going to be amazing, Robert.
그래야지, 보든 마술이
점점 인기야
Well, it has to be.
Borden's trick is getting noticed.
극장이 만원이었어
The place was packed today.
또 갔어요?
You went and saw his show again.
자넬 만날 준비됐나?
Ready to meet yourself, Mr. Angier?
내가 술에 취하면
AII I have to do is keep myself drunk...
판박이겠네요
...and no one will be able
to tell the difference.
빈정대지 마
Have a Iittle faith, sir.
시범 좀 보여주겠나, 루트?
Now, would you favor us
with a performance, Mr. Root?
Jesus.
나만큼 세상을 알면
술독에 빠져 살겠지
Yes, you would drink too
if you knew the world half as well as I do.
당신은 별 거 아냐
Did you think you were unique?
시저나 파우스트도
돼봤는데
I have been Caesar. I played Faust.
그레이트 단톤
흉내가 뭐 어려워?
How difficult could it possibly be
to play the Great Danton?
싫다면 계속 술독에
빠져 살던가
You can go back to being yourself now,
Root, for nothing.
아뇨, 할 거요
I'd rather be him for now.
아주
I find it amusing.
재밌겠거든
"그 어떤 죄인도
거부하지 않겠다"
My Iiege, I did deny no prisoners.
- 멋져요
- 고맙군
-You Iook wonderful.
-Oh, thank you.
사람들 눈에 안 띄게
숨겨야 돼
Root has to keep a Iow profile.
Anyone sees him, the game's up.
대단해요, 커터
나라면 못해요
I don't know how you do these things.
I'm not sure I wanna know.
마술 이름은 정했나?
Have you thought
what we should call the trick?
당당하게 나가야죠
보든 마술은 순간 이동이니...
There's no point in being coy. Borden
calls his trick "The Transported Man."
'새로운 순간 이동'
지금까지 보신 건
Ladies and gentlemen,
much of what you've seen tonight...
재미를 위한
눈속임에 불과해요
...may be termed as illusions
or entertaining trifles.
하지만!
AIas...
다음 마술은
차원이 다르죠
...I cannot claim
this next feat as illusion.
잘 보세요
Watch carefully.
눈속임이 아닙니다
You'II see no trickery...
진짜 마술이죠
...for no trickery is employed.
극소수 동양인들과
히말라야의
Merely a technique familiar
to certain citizens of the Orient...
성자들만 아는 마술이죠
...and various holy men
of the Himalayas.
보신 분도 있겠지만
Indeed, many of you
may be familiar with this technique...
처음 보시는 분도
걱정 마세요
...but for those of you who aren't,
do not be alarmed...
어떤 마술보다도
안전하니까요
...what you're about to see
is considered safe.
성공을 위하여!
To our achievement.
관객들 반응이 끝내줬어
The manager says
he's never seen a reaction Iike it.
재주는 곰이 부리고
관객들 환호는
At Ieast he got to see it.
I spent the ovation hiding under the stage.
마지막에 나타나는
No one cares about the man
who disappears into the box.
주정뱅이 몫이군요
They care about the one who comes out.
- 난 곰이 좋은걸요
- 고맙군
-I care about the man in the box.
-Thank you.
역할을 바꾸면 어때요?
I don't know. Maybe--
Maybe we could switch before the trick.
루트가 숨는 걸로
I could be the Prestige
and Root ends up below.
긴장감이 떨어져서 안돼
No, the anticipation of the trick
is everything.
자네의 쇼맨십이
스릴을 배가시켜
We need your showmanship
to build up the suspense.
루트 말재주론 어림없어
Once Root opens his mouth, it's over.
He can't introduce this trick.
내가 어때서?
그레이트 단톤인데!
Of course I can. I'm the Great Danton.
루트, 그 옷 벗어
분장도 지우고!
Root, you bloody fool.
Get out of that wardrobe and makeup.
누가 들어올지 몰라!
Anyone could walk in here at any minute.
축하하네
Congratulations, all.
삶이 항상 이렇게
즐겁진 않잖아요
Life is not full of these moments, Robbie.
We worked hard.
제대로 즐겨요
We need to celebrate properly.
왜 그래요?
아내 때문에?
What's wrong? Is it your wife?
마술이 완전하질 않아
No. No, it's the trick.
It isn't good enough.
보든 마술보단
훨씬 멋지잖아요
Borden's trick is nothing compared to ours.
He has no style.
그는 무대 밑에
숨진 않아
Well, he doesn't spend the finale
hiding under the stage.
비법을 알아야 돼
I need to know how he does it.
왜요?
-Why?
-So I can do it better.
더 잘해야지
조수로 들어가
I need you to go and work for him.
내가요?
농담해요?
Work for him? Are you joking?
- 내 스파이가 돼
- 뜨니까 그만둬라?
You'II be my spy.
We just got our start.
You want me to Ieave?
멀리 내다봐야지
잘 생각해봐
That's how we advance.
Think of it, OIivia.
지금도 관객들이 열광하는데
제대로만 하면
We got people excited, but imagine
what we could do with the real illusion.
역사상 가장 위대한
마술이 될 거야
We'd have the greatest magic act
anyone's ever seen.
당신 조수인 걸 알잖아요
He knows I work for you.
내 비법을 캐내려고
알고도 고용할 거야
Exactly why he'II wanna hire you.
He'II want my secret.
- 날 믿을까요?
- 사실대로 말해
-Why would he trust me?
-Because you're gonna tell him the truth.
좋아
Good girl.
어떤 기계인지
무척 궁금할 거요
You must be curious to see what
so much money has bought you, Mr. Angier.
첫 가동의 순간을
당신도 봐야지요
It's fitting you should be here
for maiden voyage.
모자 좀
Your hat.
뒤로 물러서요
You might wanna stand back.
뭐죠?
I don't understand.
고칠 테니 돌아가요
Perhaps it would be best
if you Ieft us to it.
뭐가 문제죠?
-Is there a problem, Mr. Tesla?
-No, no, no.
다음주에 와요
그땐 작동할 거요
-Come back next week.
-Next week?
-Come back-- Next week, it'II be fine.
-Tesla.
종종 말썽을 부려서...
She's just a Iittle temperamental
sometimes.
- 작업실이 흥미롭네요
- 쓸만해
-Interesting workshop.
-Yeah, we make do.
- 올리비아예요
- 알아
-My name is OIivia Wenscombe--
-I know who you are.
비밀 캐러 왔나?
You here to steal my show?
부족한 걸 주려구요
I'm here to give it what it's missing.
- 그게 뭔데?
- 나요
-Yeah? What might that be?
-Me.
내가 필요하다 했지?
여자의 손길!
I was just saying that, wasn't I, Bernard?
Woman's touch.
앤지어를 떠났어요
-I've Ieft Angier.
-AII right.
일이 필요해요
-I want a job.
-Yeah?
- 날 못 믿겠지만...
- 내가 왜?
-I know you've no reason to trust me--
-Why wouldn't I trust you?
라이벌의
유일한 여잔데!
I mean, you're only the mistress
of my enemy. Why wouldn't I trust you?
- 보든 씨
- 알프레드
-Mr. Borden--
-AIfred.
사실대로 말할게요
I'm going to tell you the truth.
마술사 세계에
진실이란 없어
Now that is a slippery notion
in our Iine of work...
...isn't it, Miss Wenscombe?
앤지어가 보냈어요
I am here because he sent me here.
비법을 알아오라고
He wants me to work for you
and steal your secret.
그가 왜?
What does he need my secret for?
지금도 감쪽같은데
His trick is top-notch.
무대에서 사라졌다
반대쪽에서
He vanishes and then he reappears
on the other side of the stage...
과묵한 술꾼으로 변해
나타나잖아
...mute, overweight and,
unless I'm mistaken, very drunk.
어떻게 하는 거지?
It's astonishing. How does he do it?
궁금하군
And tell me, OIivia, does he enjoy
taking his bows under the stage?
무대 밑에서
갈채를 즐기나?
당신 마술 비법에
굉장히 집착해요
No, it's killing him.
He's obsessed
with discovering your methods.
지금 성공엔
He thinks of nothing else.
만족 못하겠대요
그래서 떠났죠
He takes no pleasure in our success,
and I've had enough.
그와는 미래가 없으니까
There is no future with him.
그의 마술 비법을
알려줄게요
He sent me here to steal your secrets,
but I've actually come to offer you his.
그게 진실이군
This is the truth, is it?
그런가?
옷 갈아입어
Think you'd better get dressed, sir.
오늘은 더 취했군
Root, you're Iate
and more drunk than usual.
당장 내려가
-Now, get down below stairs right away.
-No.
아니, 얘기 좀 합시다
No, we need to have
a Iittle chat, Mr. Cutter.
보든이 건너편 극장에서
공연해요
We have a problem.
Cutter, Borden is performing
right across the street.
진짜 문제는
Yeah? We have a bigger problem.
루트야
돈을 더 달래
Root. He's realized
he can make demands.
협박해요?
Wha--? He's blackmailing us?
예상은 했었지만
생각보다 빠르군
I was surprised, to tell you the truth.
It usually takes them Ionger to figure it out.
- 얼마 달래요?
- 상관없어
-Well, how much does he want?
-Well, it makes no difference.
- 공연을 중단해야 돼
- 중단하다뇨?
-We gotta stop doing the trick.
-Stop the trick? Cutter, Iook at this.
- 커터, 이걸 봐요
- 지난주 신문은
Well, Iook at yesterday's,
Iook at Iast week...
자넬 런던 최고의
공연가라 극찬했어
...where they said you were
the premier stage performer in London.
마술사가 아닌
Not magician, mind you.
- 공연가!
- 그래서요?
-Performer of any kind.
-Well, what's your point?
높이 오르는 새일수록
My point is, Robert,
is you've climbed too high...
추락의 고통은 더 커
...to get away
with professional embarrassment.
통제할 수 없는
마술은 안돼
We don't do any tricks we can't control.
달라는 대로 줘요
Just pay him whatever he wants for now.
일단은 계속 하면서
그만둘 기회를 보죠
We keep doing the trick until Borden opens
and then we'II phase it out.
좋아
AII right.
루트의 요구는
갈수록 심해졌다
Cutter was always surprised
how fast Root turned bad.
나한테 술을 사는
이유가?
To what do I owe the pleasure
of this rather welcome pint of ale?
그레이트 단톤이죠?
You're the Great Danton, aren't you?
그렇소, 팬들 몰려드니
소문내지 마쇼
Of course I am, but don't advertise it
because I'II be mobbed with fans.
술독에 빠져 살기에
We paid him enough
to keep him in beers...
충분한 돈을 주었다
...so you wouldn 't expect him
to rock the boat.
보신 분도 있겠지만
Indeed, many of you
may be familiar with this technique.
처음 보시는 분들도
절대 놀라지 마세요
But for those of you who aren't,
do not be alarmed...
안전한 마술입니다
...what you're about to see
is considered safe.
선생은?
And who are you?
당신처럼 되고 싶은
무명 마술사지요
I am a humble admirer
and a fellow practitioner.
그렇군
Very good.
- 한잔 더?
- 좋지
-Another?
-Oh, if you insist.
오늘은 좀 한가하군
-Another.
-I'm not performing tonight.
Well, I'm only doing one show...
아랫사람들이
...but to be frank, my people
pretty much run things these days.
알아서 다 준비하니까
올라가!
Get up there!
빨리!
Get up!
순간 이동 마술...
Your illusion, The Transported Man...
비법을 캐내려는 건
아니지만
...I'm not claiming
to know your methods or anything...
비슷한 마술을 했는데
대역을 썼죠
...but I had a similar trick in my act,
and I used a double.
그랬군요
I see. Very good.
근데 틀어졌죠
Well, it was, and then it went bad.
대역으로 고용한
사람한테
What I didn't count on, was that
when I incorporated this bloke into my act...
주도권을 뺏겼거든
...he had complete power over me.
주도권을?
Complete power, you say.
커튼 내려!
내려!
대역한테 너무 많은
힘을 주지마요
Be very careful giving someone
that power over you.
고맙소
Well, thank you.
충고 명심하리다
Yes, thank you for the warning.
마셔요
Cheers.
눈속임이 아닙니다
I cannot claim this next feat as illusion.
아주 안전한 마술이죠
What you're about to see
is considered safe.
그레이트 단톤!
The Great Danton.
사과 드리죠
I apologize.
건너편 극장에서
공연하는데
There simply is too much magic...
제 마술이 여기까지
영향을 줬네요
...for my stage at the Pantages
across the street.
-Bravo!
방해해서 죄송합니다!
Pardon my intrusion.
너그러이 봐주세요
-Bravo!
-And go easy on the poor chap.
열심히 하잖습니까!
He does try so very hard.
꼭꼭 숨겨놨었는데
I don't know how Borden found him.
어떻게 찾아낸 거지?
Kept him under wraps, I was careful.
찾아냈잖아요
Yeah, well, he did.
올리비아 짓일까?
Do you think it was her?
놀랐어?
You weren't expecting me?
기다렸어요
오후에 온댔잖아요
I was expecting you sooner.
Your message said afternoon.
다리가 이래서
좀 늦었지
It takes a bit
for me to get around these days.
놈이 전부 뺏어갔어
He's taken everything from me.
아내, 공연
너까지!
My wife, my career, now you.
당신이 날...
What do you mean?
You sent me--
그를 도와주고 있잖아!
I sent you to steal his secret,
not to improve his act.
- 내 역할인걸요
- 사랑하잖아!
-That's my job.
-Or fall in Iove.
시킨 대로 했어요!
-I did everything you asked!
-Yes? Yes?
- 비법이 뭐지?
- 대역을 써요
-Then how does he do it?
-Cutter was right, a double.
- 어련할까!
- 대역이 쓰는
-Of course Borden said that.
-He didn't say anything. I've seen things.
분장 도구를
무대 뒤에 숨겨놨어요
Makeup, glasses, wigs. We don't use it
for the show, but I've seen it backstage.
네가 보라고
일부러 늘어놓은 거야
It's misdirection. He Ieaves things around
to make you think he's using a double.
날 의심 안 해요
AII the time?
He doesn't know when I Iook.
정신 차려, 올리비아
AII the time, OIivia!
교활한 놈이야!
That's who he is! That's what it takes!
삶 자체가 속임수라구!
He Iives his act! Don't you see?
동침하는 사이라고
널 믿는 건 아냐
Just because you're sleeping with him
doesn't mean he trusts you.
다 안다고 착각 마요!
You think you can see everything,
don't you?
보려 하질 않잖아!
But the Great Danton is a blind fool.
His notebook.
그의 노트예요
훔쳤어?
You stole it?
다시 갖다놔야 돼요
I borrowed it for tonight.
이걸 베끼고...
I thought you could translate it,
but now--
- 못해
- 못해요?
-I can't.
-You can't?
암호화 돼 있어서
아무도 못 풀어
OIivia, no one can, it's a cipher.
암호를 알아도
수 개월은 걸려
Even with the keyword
it would take months to decode.
- 암호를 모르면?
- 평생 못 풀겠지
-And without the keyword?
-Perhaps never.
아침까지 안 갖다두면
들킨다구요
-We'II see.
-We will not see.
If I don't get that back to him tomorrow,
he'II know I took it.
- 그를 떠나
- 찾아올 거예요
-Leave him.
-I can't. He knows where I Iive.
놈의 일기야
This is his diary, OIivia.
놈의 모든 비밀이
내 손에 들려 있어
AII of his secrets
are right here in my hands.
- 아내 일은 잊어요
- 비법만 알면 돼
Won't bring your wife back.
I don't care about my wife,
I care about his secret.
Look...
강도 든 것처럼 위장할게
...I'II go to his workshop
and stage a break-in.
- 눈치 챌 거예요
- 하지만 넌 무사하지
-He'II know you took it.
-Yes, me. Not you.
알겠어?
Understand?
Robert.
그를 사랑해요
I have fallen in Iove with him.
그동안 힘들었겠군
Then I know how hard
this has been for you.
노트가 없어?
Notebook?
이제 시작이군
Then he's just getting started.
안녕하시오
-Good evening.
-Professor.
Professor.
-Here.
-Could I get your autograph?
걸어갈게
-I'm walking tonight.
-Professor.
앤지어가 와도 상관없어
Let him come. I don't care.
-Professor.
- 괜찮아요?
- 죽진 않았어
-You all right?
-I'm alive.
공기구멍 내는
수고는 덜었군!
Saves me cutting you an air hole.
- 대단해
- 뭐가?
-I'm impressed.
-Why's that?
손을 더럽혔잖아
You're finally getting your hands dirty.
진짜 마술사가 됐어
It's what a good trick costs, Angier.
모험
Risk.
희생
Sacrifice.
원하는 걸 안 주면
희생은 네 몫이지
The sacrifice, I'm afraid, is gonna be yours,
unless you give me what I want.
- 뭐지?
- 네 비법!
-Which is?
-Your secret.
비법?
My secret?
순간 이동 비법!
Your method for The Transported Man.
팔론은 입에
자물쇠를 채웠더군
Fallon wouldn't tell me.
He doesn't seem to talk at all.
노트 가져갔잖아
You have my notebook.
암호 모르면 소용없어
Useless without the keyword.
비법을 적어
Write down your method, Mr. Borden.
자세하게!
Describe it in full.
암호가 아닌 비법을...
I want the whole method,
not the keyword.
전부 알아야겠어
I don't even know
if your secret's in your notebook.
암호가 비법이야
The keyword is the method.
내 조수는?
Where's my ingenieur?
- 살아 있나?
- 땅 잘 파나?
-AIive?
-How fast can you dig?
팔론!
내 목소리 들려?
Fallon! You hear me? Fallon!
- 팔은 어때요?
- 아직 붙어 있어
-How's the arm?
-Still attached.
답을 얻었나?
-Did you find your answer?
-Our answer.
아뇨, 우리가
함께 찾아야죠
Cutter, I haven't Iooked yet.
I wanted you to share this.
난 벌써 알아
I already know how he does it, Robert.
우리가 하는 거랑 똑같애
The same way he always has.
The same way as we do.
자넨 그 이상을
원할 뿐이지
It's just that you want something more.
그럼 알아볼까요?
Well, Iet's find out then,
shall we?
무슨 뜻이지?
What does it mean?
'테슬라'
미국에 다녀와야겠군요
It means, Cutter,
we have a journey ahead of us.
-To America.
-Robert?
로버트?
잘 들어
Listen to me.
집착은 젊은이의
전유물이야
Obsession is a young man's game.
- 말도 안돼요
- 더는 못 도와줘
-Oh, come on.
-I can't follow you any further in it.
미안하네
I can't. I'm sorry.
혼자 가야겠군요
Then the rest is up to me.
미안해
I'm sorry.
안녕하시오
Good evening. Hello, darling.
안녕, 새라
최고급 샴페인!
Champagne, your finest.
손님 있었어?
I didn't know we were
going to be joined for dinner.
- 축하할 일이 있거든
- 웬스콤 양
-Absolutely. We are celebrating.
-Miss Wenscombe.
팔론 씨
Mr. Fallon.
Well, what are we celebrating?
뭔데?
새 마술을 개발했어
Well, we've hit upon a new trick,
haven't we, Fallon?
- 어떤 마술이요?
- 그래, 어떤 마술?
-What trick, Freddy?
-Yes, Freddy, what trick?
밤마다 나를
땅속에 묻으면
I am going to bury myself alive
every night...
누군가 파내주는 마술
멋지잖아?
...and then someone will come along
and dig me up. Wonderful.
- 그만...
- 빨리 따라요, 괜찮소
-No, I think my husband's had quite enough.
-No, pour the champagne. Come on, pour--
- 새라, 애 취급은 사양해
- 난 그냥...
Right. Sarah, don't talk to me Iike that.
I'm not a child.
남편이 취했어요
올리비아 데려다줘
-Perhaps it would--
-Perhaps, Mr. Fallon...
...you might escort Miss Wenscombe home.
My husband's being a bore.
- 왜 사서 고생이죠?
- 저녁 망치지 마
-I see no reason why you have to suffer.
-Oh, please. Don't ruin this evening.
갈게요, 보든 부인
프레디
Good night, Mrs. Borden.
Good night, Freddy.
- 프레디?
- 내 애칭이잖아
-"Freddy"?
-Well, that's my name.
- 집에선 아냐
- 집에만 있는 게 아니잖아?
-Not at home.
-Well, I'm not always at home, am I?
그 수염, 떼면 안돼?
Well, couldn't you have at Ieast
taken off the beard?
공연 끝내고 왔잖아
Sarah, I just came from
the bloody theater just now.
딴 사람들은
전부 좋아한다고
AII right? And I'm out in public.
-Everybody else Ioves it.
-Why are you being Iike this, AIfred?
왜 이러는 거야?
고통스런 하루였어
I had a terrible ordeal today.
내겐 그 무엇보다
소중한 사람을
I thought that something very precious...
잃을 뻔 했거든
...had been Iost to me.
무사한 걸
축하하는 거야
So I just wanted to celebrate.
Just a Iittle.
누굴 잃을 뻔 했는데?
AII right, what?
What did you Iose?
그것도 비밀이군
I see, more secrets.
새라
비밀은 내 삶이야
Sarah, secrets are my Iife.
- 우리의 삶!
- 당신 같지가 않아
-Our Iife.
-No, AIfred, stop.
This isn't you. Stop performing.
연기 제발 그만해
손님이 또 있었소?
I thought I had the place
to myself, Mr. Brent.
불청객이죠
Unexpected guests.
예의도 없고
많은 걸 묻더군요
Not very polite. A Iot of questions.
- 정부 요원인 줄 알았죠
- 아니오?
First I thought they might work
for the government.
토마스 에디슨
사람들이에요
-No?
-Worse.
They work for Thomas Edison.
이상한 일이 생겼다
Today, a most curious development.
앤지어 조수가
날 찾아왔다
His assistant came to us
with a proposition.
물론, 앤지어가
보낸 거다
Obviously, Angier has sent her
and told her to admit as much.
무대 밑에서
갈채를 즐기나?
Does he enjoy taking
his bows under the stage?
당신 비법을 캐오랬지만
그의 비법을 알려줄게요
He sent me here to steal your secrets,
but I've actually come to offer you his.
그게 진실이군
This is the truth, is it?
그런가?
그렇게 말하랬어요
No, that's what he told me to tell you.
The truth...
그를 사랑해서
곁을 지켰지만
...is that I Ioved him, and I stood by him,
and he sent me to you...
날 여자가 아닌
조수 취급만 했죠
...Iike he would send a stagehand
to pick up his shirts.
그를 증오해요
I hate him for that.
앤지어 마술의 비법은
알고 있어
I can spot Angier's methods
from the back of the theater.
내가 모르는 걸 말해봐
So, what could you possibly
have to offer me?
그 사람 마술이
왜 당신보다 나은진
You know how he does his tricks,
but you can't understand...
모르잖아요
이걸 숨겨서죠
...why no one can see yours are better.
You hide this.
순간 이동
공연할 때 봤어요
I had to Iook very closely to spot it when
you were performing The Transported Man...
이건 당신한텐
큰 장점이에요
...but this makes you unique.
대역을 안 쓴단 증거죠
It shows the audience
you aren't using a double.
또, 한 손으로
You mustn't hide it,
display it proudly.
마술을 한다는 것도
대단한 거죠
I'm sure it takes great skill
to perform illusions with one good hand.
그렇긴 하지
Yeah, it does.
사람들한테 보여줘요
So Iet people know.
앤지어보다 뛰어난
마술사란 걸!
You could be so much more than he is,
and I can show you how.
사실인 것 같다
I think she's telling the truth.
믿을 순 없지만
I think we cannot trust her.
그녀를 사랑한다
그녀가 필요하다
But I love her. I need her.
아내 이외의 여자를 두는
To open myself to such a relationship...
위험한 관계를
시작하려면
... to the dangers of such an affair...
믿음과 사랑의
정표가 필요하다
...I need assurances of fidelity. Of love.
하지만 어떻게?
But how to be sure?
방법이 있다
I know a way.
It's the only way to know her mind.
그녀 마음을 알
유일한 방법
왜 널 보냈지?
How could he send you away?
앤지어를 없애게
도와줄 거다
She must help me rid ourselves
of Angier.
오늘, 그녀의 진심을
확인했다
Today, my mistress proves
her truthfulness.
그녀가 나를
Not to me, you understand.
루트와 만나게 해준 거다
I've been convinced
since she led me to Root.
올리비아가
나에 대한 사랑을
Today, Olivia proves her love for me
to you, Angier.
자네한테 고백했지
그래, 앤지어
Yes, Angier.
내가 시킨 대로
노트를 전했어
She gave you this notebook
at my request.
테슬라는 내 비법의
핵심이 아니야
And, yes, "Tesla " is merely the key
to my diary, not to my trick.
그렇게 쉽게 비법을
내놓을 것 같았나?
Did you really think I'd part
with my secret so easily after so much?
안녕, 앤지어
Goodbye, Angier.
미국에서 원하는 걸
얻길 빌어주지
May you find solace for your thwarted
ambition back in your American home.
테슬라!
Tesla!
앨리!
Tesla! AIIey! AIIey!
내가 부탁했던
기계가 아니오
Tesla never made a machine
Iike the one I asked for.
- 알아요
- 난 몰랐어!
-We never said he had.
-But you Iet me believe that he had.
연구비가 필요해
날 속였군
You stole my money because
your funding had been cut off.
You've been shooting sparks at my top hat,
Iaughing at me all along...
처음부터 작정하고
모자로 현혹시키곤
...while using my money
to stave off ruin.
내 돈을 훔쳤어!
에디슨 사람들을 만났소
-Now, I have seen Edison's men.
-Where?
- 어디서요?
- 호텔에서
- 데려올 수도 있어
- 안 그러는 게 좋소
In the hotel. And I have every mind
to bring them up here myself.
That would be unwise, Mr. Angier.
당신 돈을 쓴 건
사실이지만
It is true that you are
our Iast remaining financier...
훔치진 않았소
...but we have not stolen your money.
고양일 왜?
Sir, my cat.
기계를 만들어준다는 건
진짜였소
When I told you I could make
your machine, I spoke a simple truth.
그럼 왜 효과가 없지?
-Then why isn't the machine working?
-Because exact science, Mr. Angier...
과학은 확률의
싸움일 뿐이오
...is not an exact science.
기대한 효과가
없는 것이지요
The machine simply does not operate
as expected.
연구가 더 필요해요
It requires further examination.
- 모자는 어디로?
- 아무 데도
-So where did my top hat go?
-Nowhere.
수십번 해봤지만
We tried the damn thing a dozen times.
그대로였소
The hat went nowhere.
실험 대상을 바꾸면
We need to try different material.
다른 결과가
나올 수도 있소
It may provoke a different result.
이리 와
Copernicus, come on.
고양이가 잘못되면
박사님 책임이에요
You are responsible for whatever happens
to this animal, doctor.
쓸모 없는 기계에
돈만 날린 꼴이군
I hope that whatever you were really doing
with my money was more worthwhile...
...Mr. Tesla.
앨리!
AIIey!
효과가 있었소!
So the machine was working.
모자가 그대로여서
측정하지 않았어요
I never bothered to check the calibration
because the hat never moved.
과학은 항상
뜻밖의 결과를 가져오지
These things never quite work
as you expect them to, Mr. Angier.
그게 바로 과학의 묘미요
That's one of the principal
beauties of science.
문제를 해결하려면
몇 주 걸릴 거요
I'II need a couple of weeks to iron out
the problems with the machine.
완성되면 연락하리다
We'II send word when it's ready.
모자 가져가요
Don't forget your hat.
어떤 거죠?
-Well, which one is mine?
-They're all your hats, Mr. Angier.
전부 당신 거요
새 드레스가 아주 예쁘다
You Iook so pretty
in this new dress of yours.
- 동물원에 가?
- 아니, 아빠는 바빠
-Are we going to the zoo this afternoon?
-No, no, no. Daddy has some errands to run.
- 약속했잖아
- 내가?
-But you promised.
-I promised, did I?
그럼 가야지
Then go to the zoo we shall.
볼일 보고 올 테니
준비하고 있으렴
So Daddy will go run his errands
and I'II be back before you know it...
...so you go get ready.
We'II go see those chimpanzees.
침팬지 구경가자
Sarah.
뭐해?
What are you doing?
서방질보단 술이 낫잖아
We each of us have our vices.
분명히 말하지만
Sarah, whatever you may think...
나한텐 당신과
제스뿐이야
...your only competition for my affections
is our Iittle girl.
당신을 사랑해
영원히 당신만을!
I Iove you. I will always Iove you
and you alone.
- 오늘은 진심이네
- 물론!
-You mean it today.
-Absolutely.
그래서 더 힘들어
종잡을 수 없거든
Which makes it so much harder
when you don't.
쇼핑 목록?
돈에 환장했군
Is that more shopping?
She does Iove the smell of money.
딸이 동물원 가재
갔다 올 수 있지?
The Iittle Iady wants to go to the zoo,
so I thought you could take her.
아님 내일 내가 갈게
Yeah? I mean,
I can do it tomorrow if not.
그리고 새라가
And Sarah, she knows.
눈치챘어
전부는 아니라도
뭔가 이상하단 걸
She-- I mean, at Ieast she knows
that something's not right...
네가 도와줘야겠어
...so if you can just do whatever you can
to help me with her.
잘 얘기해서
내가 사랑한단 걸
Talk to her. Just convince her
that I do Iove her.
확인시켜줘
- 왜 그래요, 프레디?
- 그렇게 부르지 마
-What is it, Freddy?
-Just don't call me that, please.
아무것도 아냐
It's nothing. It's just, you know,
there's sometimes....
- 잘못하는 거 같아서
- 나랑 있을 땐
-Sometimes it seems wrong.
-I've told you before...
나만 생각해요
가족은 잊어요
...when you're with me,
you're with me.
Leave your family at home
where they belong.
노력하고 있어
I'm trying.
노력한다고
I'm trying, OIivia.
옷 입을게요
-I'II get dressed.
-Yeah.
팔론이 왔었어요
I saw Fallon hanging around again.
믿음이 안 가요
There's something
about that man I don't trust.
날 믿는다면
You trust me? Then trust Fallon.
그 사람도 믿어
내 분신과도 같은
사람이야
He protects the things that I care about.
떠나신다니 유감이군요
We're sorry to see you go, Mr. Angier.
테슬라 씨가 떠난 것도요
We were sorry to see
Mr. Tesla Ieave as well.
마을의 은인이시죠
He was very good to Colorado Springs.
앤지어 씨
Mr. Angier, I didn't think it was necessary
to tell Edison's men about the box.
에디슨 사람들한텐
말 안 했어요
뭘 말이오?
What box?
'앤지어 씨'
작별 인사도 없이
떠나서 미안하오
I apologize for leaving
without saying goodbye...
이젠 콜로라도를
떠날 때가 됐소
...but I seem to have outstayed
my welcome in Colorado.
난 과학계의 인정을
못 받았지만
The truly extraordinary is not
permitted in science and industry.
당신은 미스터리를 즐기는
Perhaps you'll find more luck in your field,
where people are happy to be mystified.
사람들로부터
환영 받길 바라오
당신이 원하는 게
상자에 들었소
You will find what
you are looking for in this box.
앨리가 사용법을 적었고
Alley has written you
a thorough set of instructions.
난 한가지 조언만
덧붙였소
I add only one suggestion
on using the machine:
파괴하시오
Destroy it.
바닷속에 버려요
Drop it to the bottom
of the deepest ocean.
불행을 몰고 올
기계니까!
Such a thing will bring you only misery.
난 테슬라 경고에
귀 기울이지 않았다
Tesla 's warning is as unheeded
as he knew it would be.
오늘 기계를 시험했다
Today, I tested the machine...
제대로 작동한다는
보장은 없었지만...
... taking precautions in case Tesla
hadn 't ironed out the kinks in its operation.
만약 잘못된다 해도
이대로 살 순 없다
I mean, if it went wrong,
I would not wanna live like that for long.
이젠 자네를
떠날 때가 됐어
But here at the Turn,
I must leave you, Borden.
보든 자네를...
Yes, you, Borden.
감방에 앉아
Sitting there in your cell...
내 일기를 읽으며
...reading my diary, awaiting your death...
내가 선사한 죽음을
기다리겠지
...for my murder.
앤지어 일기는 가짜요
Angier' s journal, that gesture
of good faith, that' s a fake.
그렇지 않소
I assure you, it's not. The provenance
of the journal is clear and under no doubt.
일기의 진위엔
의심의 여지가 없소
앤지어가 직접
자필로 작성했죠
And it's written in Angier's own hand,
of which we had numerous examples.
상관없소
It don't matter.
내 마술의 비법이오
So my tricks.
- 전부 다!
- 순간 이동까지?
-AII of them.
-Including The Transported Man?
콜드로 경께서
기뻐하실 겁니다
Well, Lord Caldlow
will be very pleased indeed.
아니
No, he won't.
Because they're not complete.
완벽한 비법은 아뇨
마지막 단계가
빠져 있으니까
It's just the PIedge
and the Turn for each.
프레스티지가 빠졌다면
Without the Prestige for these tricks...
쓸모가 없잖소
-...these are worthless.
-Yeah.
내일 딸을 데려오면
알려주겠소
You get the rest of it
when you bring my daughter here.
마지막으로 보고 싶소
I wanna say goodbye.
아니, 지금 말해!
We have to go through it now.
Listen, we have to go through it now.
Now, Iisten to me.
잡아떼도 소용없어!
Deny it all you want.
올리비아랑
그런 사이 아냐
OIivia means nothing.
공연에 필요한
조수일 뿐이지
-OIivia?
-I need an assistant.
No, I'II go to her.
- 말할 거야
- 뭘?
-I'II tell her I know--
-Tell her what?
당신 정체를 알아
알프레드
I know what you really are, AIfred. I....
- 더는 못 숨기겠어
- 말하면 안돼
-I know, and I--
-Sarah, Sarah.
-I can't keep it in.
-You can't talk Iike this.
새라, 입 다물어
Sarah, shut up.
-No, no.
-Sarah, shut up!
닥치라구!
I don't wanna hear it anymore!
듣기 싫으니까
입 닥쳐!
You can't talk Iike this!
숨겨도 소용없어
난 알아
You can't hide it anymore
because I know, AIfred, I know.
당신 진짜 모습을!
I know what you really are!
AIfred...
이렇겐 못 살아
...I can't Iive Iike this.
난 좋은지 알아?
Oh, well, you think I can Iive Iike this?
이렇게 사는 걸
즐긴다고 생각해?
You think I bloody enjoy Iiving Iike this?
- 들어봐!
- 넓은 집, 사랑스런 딸...
-Stop it and Iisten! No!
-We have this beautiful house...
우린 부부야!
뭐가 불만이야?
...Iovely Iittle girl, we're married.
What is so wrong with your Iife?
이렇겐 못 살아!
AIfred, I can't Iive Iike this!
원하는 게 뭐야?
Well, what do you want from me?
솔직하게 말해줘
I want....
I want you to be honest with me.
속임수
No tricks...
거짓말
...no Iies...
비밀은 집어치워
...and no secrets.
날 사랑해?
Do you--? Do you Iove me?
오늘은 아냐
Not today.
아니
No.
누구요?
Who's there?
옛 친구를 찾소
I'm Iooking for an old friend.
공연 잡아준댔죠?
I heard about a booking.
아담한 극장에서?
Nice Iittle theater.
Good up-and-coming magician.
- 돌아왔군
- 반가워요
-You're back.
-It's good to see you, John.
연습하기 좋은 곳이군
Good rehearsal space.
일꾼도 장님이고
BIind stagehands, I Iike it.
자넨 관객 취향을 잘 알지
You always had
a good eye for publicity.
날 도와줘요
I need your help, John.
마지막 공연이에요
It's my Iast show. A Iimited engagement.
마지막 공연?
Your Iast show?
집착은 젊은이의
전유물이랬죠?
A wise man once told me
obsession was a young man's game.
이젠 끝났어요
I'm almost done.
한가지만 남았죠
There's one thing Ieft.
진짜 순간 이동!
The Real Transported Man.
그걸 무대에 올리겠다?
You wanna design a show around it.
이번엔 전면에서
공연을 끌어줘요
I don't want you backstage.
I need you front of house, managing.
모든 줄 동원해서
I need you to call in favors
or connections you have...
- 극장 잡아줘요
- 어떤 극장?
-...to get us the right booking for the run.
-What sort of booking you after?
보든도 감탄할 극장을!
The sort that Borden can't ignore.
오랜만에 뵙는군요
What an honor it is to see you again, sir.
어떤 마술인지
호기심이 발동했소
You told me you only wanted to show me
one trick. It piqued my interest.
- 엄청난 마술이죠
- 반갑습니다
-It's a very clever trick, Mr. Ackerman.
-PIeased to meet you.
마찬가질세
그럼 시작하게
Likewise, I'm sure.
Well, Iet's get on, shall we?
시작해
Turn it on, gentlemen.
멋지군
Very pretty.
그게 다요?
사라지는 거?
That's it, Cutter? He simply disappears?
진짜 마술이라면
다시 나타나야지
That's not a trick.
Well, he has to come back.
- 그게...
- 프레스티지?
There has to be a--
그렇네
-A Prestige?
-Exactly.
날 용서하게
Pardon me.
진짜 마술을 보는 건
It's very rare to see...
흔치 않지
...real magic.
- 이게 얼마만에...
- 도와줄 겁니까?
-Yes, it's been many years since I've seen--
-Are you interested in helping us?
좋아
Yes.
지금처럼은 안되고
But you'II have to dress it up a Iittle.
좀 감춰
Disguise it.
관객이 의심하게...
Give them enough reason to doubt it.
아내 얘긴
한번도 안 하네요
You haven't spoken about her, Freddy.
Not once.
너한테 왜
아내 얘길 하겠어?
Why would I talk about her to you?
당신 삶의 일부였고
Because she was a part of your Iife.
이젠 죽었으니까
And now she's gone.
자살한 날
나한테 만나쟀어요
You know, the day before she killed herself,
she said she wanted to meet me.
당신에 대해
말해준다면서
That she had something
to tell me about you.
그렇지만
만날 용기가 없었죠
I was such a coward,
I couldn't bring myself to face her.
But...
무슨 얘기였을까요?
...what would she have said?
진실을 알고 싶어?
You wanna know the truth about me?
단 한 순간도
Truth is that...
그녈 사랑한 적 없어
...I never Ioved Sarah.
한 순간도!
I never Ioved her.
결혼해서
애까지 낳았잖아요
-You married her. You had a child with her.
-Yes, yes. Part of me.
내 일부가 그랬지
Part of me did, but the other part didn't.
난 아냐
난 널 찾았고
여기 앉아 있어
The part that found you.
The part that's sitting here right now.
널 사랑해
I Iove you.
사랑해, 올리비아
그게 진실이야
No, OIivia, I Iove you. That's the truth.
중요한 건 그뿐이지
That is the truth that matters.
다른 장소에서
딴 여자한테도
You could be in some other restaurant
with some other woman right now...
그렇게 말하겠죠
...talking about me that way.
- 아니
- 맞아요
-No.
-Yes.
당신은 섬뜩할 정도로
냉정해요
It's inhuman to be so cold.
그가 돌아왔어요
He's back. After two years.
2년 만에...
새 마술이 있는데
최고래요
He's got a new trick. They're saying
it's the best London's ever seen.
얼굴 표정 볼만 하네요
You should see the Iook
on your face, Professor.
가서 만나봐요
You should go to him.
라이벌이잖아요
You two deserve each other.
극장은 이미 예약됐소
모스크바 발레단이 내년까지
I'm afraid I'm booked. The Moscow Ballet,
they'II be playing through next year.
계약 해지해요
100회만 공연할 거요
Then get rid of them.
There'II be a hundred performances.
No more, no Iess.
주당 5회씩 밤에만
Five performances a week. No matinees.
그게 입장료요
그럼...
And that's what you'II be charging
for each ticket. Good day.
지금부터 보실 마술은
Ladies and gentlemen,
my first trick of the evening...
대단히 위험합니다
...is one that involves considerable risk.
사고 났던 공연을 보고
충격을 받았던 분들은
Anyone in the audience
who would be irrevocably damaged...
...by seeing a man drown
should Ieave now.
지금 나가십시오
이 마술을
알려줬던 아가씨는
For when I tell you the young Iady
who taught me this illusion...
공연 중에 죽었죠
...actually died performing it...
얼마나 위험한지
알게 될 겁니다
...you will understand the seriousness
of the dangers involved.
시작하죠
Let's begin.
여행을 갔다가
미래를 봤어요
In my travels, I have seen the future...
아주 기괴한 미래죠
...and it is a strange future indeed.
이 세상엔
The world, Iadies and gentlemen...
새롭고 무시무시한
가능성이 존재해요
...is on the brink of new
and terrifying possibilities.
이제 보실 것은
마술이 아닙니다
What you're about to witness
is not magic.
과학이죠
It is purely science.
무대로 올라오셔서
I would Iike to invite you
to come up on-stage now...
기계를 살펴보세요
...so that you can examine the machine
for yourselves.
인간의 능력은
상상력을 뛰어넘죠
Man's reach exceeds his imagination.
Bravo!
Bravo! Bravo!
Bravo. Bravo.
100회 공연!
One hundred performances.
이유가 뭐지?
Why? Does his method dictate that?
단순한 홍보 수단?
Is it a publicity move? What is it?
놈이 런던 최고의
마술사로 불려, 왜?
He's a no-talent magician,
and they're calling him...
...the bloody best in England. Why?
45미터를 이동했어
단 1초 만에!
Fifty yards in a second. In a second!
비밀문이 있다는 것 외엔
아무것도 몰라
And all that we know
is he uses a trap door.
무대 밑에
뭐가 있는 거야?
Brilliant. What is going on
under that stage?
왜 못 알아내?
Why can't you outthink him?
매일 밤 저래
They do this every night?
공연이 끝난 후에...
After each performance, yeah?
'그레이트 단톤
진정한 순간 이동'
우리가 졌어
We're done.
알았어?
AII right?
다 끝난 거야
Let him have his trick.
비법은 필요 없어
I don't need-- I don't need his secret.
그러니까
So...
다신 찾아가지 마
...don't go back there,
you Ieave him alone.
우리 둘 다
Both of us, just Ieave him alone.
이젠 물러나는 거야
We're done.
말했잖아요
I told you, John...
무대 뒤엔 오지 마요
...I don't want you backstage
on this one.
무대로 올라오셔서
I would Iike to invite you
to come up on-stage now...
기계를 살펴보세요
...so that you can examine the machine
for yourselves.
- 어디 가는데?
- 난 단원이야!
-Hey, you, where do you think you're going?
-I'm part of the bloody act, you fool.
누구였지?
Who was that?
Hey!
열쇠 어딨어?
Where's the bloody key?
장님이 가졌어!
The blind man's got it!
열쇠 가져와!
죽는다구!
Where's the bloody key?
BIoody drowning!
조금만 참아!
Hold on!
무슨 짓을 한 거야?
What have you done?
알프레드 보든,
앤지어 살해 혐의로
AIfred Borden, you have been found guilty
of the murder of Robert Angier.
교수형에 처한다
You will be hanged by the neck
until dead.
신의 가호가 있길!
May the Lord have mercy on your soul.
커터 씨?
Mr. Cutter?
오웬스입니다
Owens.
와줘서 고맙소
Oh, thank you for coming, Mr. Owens.
앤지어 장비 처분을
맡았는데
It has fallen to me to dispose
of Mr. Angier's equipment.
콜드로 경이
But I noticed from this manifest...
대부분 구입했군요
...that Lord Caldlow
has purchased the bulk of the items.
어디로 보낼지를
묻는 거라면...
Mr. Cutter, if you needed to know
where to deliver these items, surely you--
아뇨, 장비 하나를
No, no. It's just
there is one particular item...
내가 샀으면 하는데...
...this item, in fact, that I would Iike to--
- 네?
- 사겠소
-You would Iike to...?
-Buy.
- 당신이?
- 그렇소
-Buy yourself?
-Yeah, I suppose so.
- 이 기계요?
- 그렇소
-This is the machine?
-Yes.
콜드로 경이
원하는 기계라서요
Well, I'm afraid Lord Caldlow was adamant
about purchasing this particular item.
직접 만났으면 좋겠는데?
Do you think I could talk
to Lord Caldlow in person?
그건 불가능합니다
Out of the question, I'm afraid.
허나...
Of course...
장비들을
배달하는 과정에서
...I suppose if, in the course
of your delivery arrangements...
우연히 만난다면
...your paths were to cross...
- 그것까지 막을 순 없죠
- 고맙소
-...I can't stop you speaking your mind.
-Thank you.
- 아직 여나?
- 지금은!
-Still here, Borden?
-For now.
콜드로 경 면회야
Got a visitor.
Lord Caldlow.
꼬마랑 왔어
With a Iittle girl.
제스?
Jess?
안녕, 아가야
Hello, my Iove.
잘 지냈어?
너무 보고 싶었어
How are you? I've missed you so much.
팔론 아저씨도
널 보고 싶대
And Fallon's missed you too.
We both have.
아빠, 들어가도 돼?
Daddy, can I come in there?
지금은 안돼
Not right now. Not right now, darling.
하지만 걱정하지 마
No, but everything is gonna be all right.
- 캘드로 경이군요
- 콜드로
-You must be Lord Caldlow.
-Caldlow.
내 진짜 이름이지
Yes, I am.
I always have been.
족쇄를 채워놨군
They flatter you
with all those chains, AIfred.
고무공 없인 탈출을
못한단 걸 모르는군
Don't they know you can't escape
without your Iittle rubber ball?
내가 널
I pulled you out.
물탱크에서 꺼냈어
Out of that tank.
마술사로서의 내 앞길을
AII I wanted to do was prove
that I was a better magician...
막지 말았어야지
...but you couldn't Ieave me alone.
어떻게 한 건진 모르지만
I don't know what you've done...
손을 더럽히기로
작정했나 보군
...but you're not afraid
to get your hands dirty anymore, are you?
이젠 아냐
No, not anymore.
난 승자니까
And I win.
사라진 사람에 대해선
아무도 신경 안 써
Because no one cares about the man
in the box, the man who disappears.
이겼다고?
You win?
이건 경쟁이 아냐
딸 삶이 걸려 있어
This ain't a bloody competition anymore,
Angier, this is my Iittle girl's Iife.
앨 결부시키지 마
And don't you dare put her
in the middle of this.
소중한 사람을 잃는
그 기분...
Oh, I know how hard it is
to have someone so special...
나도 잘 알지
...taken away from me, don't I, Borden?
딸을 못 데려가잖아?
And you can't take her with you now,
can you?
잘 돌봐줄게
Oh, she'II be Iooked after.
- 가자
- 잠깐만, 가지 마!
-Goodbye, Professor. Come on, darling.
-No, no, no. Stop, stop, stop. Look.
여기
Here.
네가 원한 거야
That's what you're after.
이걸 원했잖아
That's what this is about.
받아
Take it.
비법?
-Your secret?
-Yeah.
넌 항상 나보다 뛰어났지
You always were the better magician.
그건 인정해
We both know that.
비법이 뭐였든 간에
But whatever your secret was,
I mean, you have to agree...
내 마술이 더 뛰어나
...mine is better.
그러지 마, 안돼!
Don't do this. Don't do this, Angier, no.
Jess, Jess, Jess.
제스, 아빠가
곧 데리러 갈게
Jess, I'm gonna take you home soon.
I promise.
- 눈물나겠군
- 약속할게, 봐
-For God's sake, Borden.
-I promise. Look.
약속해
I promise.
사랑한다, 제스
사랑해
-I Iove you, Jess. I Iove you.
-Come on.
- 가자
- 사랑해
-Come on. Come on.
-I Iove you. I Iove you, Jess.
- 어서
- 사랑해, 제스
Angier. Angier!
내가 못 나갈 거 같아?
What, you think this place can hold me?
난 처형될 거야!
Angier! They're gonna bloody hang me!
그러니 이제 그만둬!
They're gonna bloody hang me!
You can put a stop to this now!
내가 죽인 사람이
바로 저 자야!
-Listen! Listen! That man--!
-Just shut up.
Listen, that man is the one
I'm meant to have killed!
내 말 들어!
You blind bastard, Iisten to me!
- 살아있잖아!
- 간수!
-If he's alive, I'm not guilty!
-Guards!
- 난 무죄야!
- 조용해!
-I'm not guilty!
-I don't care! Get hold of him!
잘 있게
-Goodbye, Professor.
-Angier!
유모한테 가
Run along now.
손님이 오셨어요
Sir. There's a gentleman waiting.
맙소사
Dear God.
커터
Hello, Cutter.
살아있잖아
You're-- You're still alive.
어떻게 된 건가?
How is it you're still alive, Robert?
죽은 걸 봤는데!
I saw you on a slab, for God's sake.
-Child.
-Good night, sir.
Good night, Jess.
저 꼬마를 알아
I've seen her before.
법정에서 봤어
I saw her in court with Fallon.
팔론과...
- 어떻게 한 거야?
- 돌봐줘야지
-What have you done?
-Well, she needs Iooking after.
아버지가 필요해
She needs her father.
보든을 죽이게
도와준 꼴이 됐어
You're Ietting him hang,
and I helped you.
그 기계를 부수라고
I came here to beg Lord Caldlow
to Iet me destroy that machine.
콜드로 경한테
부탁하러 왔는데
자네라면 부탁 않겠어
I am not gonna beg you for anything.
걱정 마
다신 안 쓸 테니
You don't have to. I'm gonna make sure
that machine's never used again.
그럼, 콜드로 경
Then, Lord Caldlow...
어디로 보내면 되겠소?
...where do you want me to deliver it?
극장에
My theater.
프레스티지
물건들과 함께
It belongs with the Prestige materials.
당신한텐 정말 미안하군
John, I tried not to involve you.
이젠
So...
각자 가는 거야
...we go alone now.
영원히...
Both of us.
난 너처럼
멀리 못 가겠지만
Only I don't have as far to go as you.
울지 마
No.
네 말처럼
물러났어야 했어
You were right, I should have Ieft him
to his damn trick.
미안해
I'm sorry.
전부 내 탓이야
I'm sorry for a Iot of things.
새라 자살도
I'm sorry about Sarah.
자살하게 만들
의도는 없었어
I didn't mean to hurt her.
I didn't.
이젠 자유롭게 살아
You go Iive your Iife in full now, all right?
내 몫까지!
You Iive for both of us.
잘 가
Goodbye.
잘 봐둬
Are you watching closely?
여기 놓게
Put it down the end.
자네가 이뤄놓은 걸
잘 감상하라고
Take a minute to consider
your achievement.
익사할 뻔한
선원 얘길 했었지?
I once told you about a sailor
who described drowning to me.
그래, 고향처럼
편안했다고
Yes, he said it was Iike going home.
거짓말이야
I was Iying. He said it was agony.
고통스러웠댔어
알프레드 보든
AIfred Borden...
영국 왕과
고등법원 이름으로
...this day, in the name of the king
and the High Court of England...
교수형을 집행한다
...you will meet your end.
사라진 사람에 대해선
아무도 신경 안 써
No one cares about the man in the box.
Cutter?
마지막으로 할 말은?
Do you have anything to say?
Abracadabra.
형제였군
A brother.
쌍둥이 형제
A twin.
넌 팔론이었어
You were Fallon the whole time.
처음부터...
둘 다
No.
팔론이자
We were both Fallon.
보든이었지
And we were both Borden.
사라진 사람은
누구였지?
Were you--? Were you the one
who went into the box...
너? 아님 동생?
...or the one who came back out?
그때그때 달랐지
We took turns.
그게 마술의 비법이었어
The trick is where we would swap.
커터도 그랬지만
난 너무 쉽다고 했어
Cutter knew. Cutter knew.
But I told him it was too simple, too easy.
간단했지만 쉽진 않았지
No.
Simple maybe, but not easy.
둘이 한 사람의 삶을
사는 게 쉽진 않거든
There's nothing easy
about two men sharing one life.
왜 또 피가 나지?
I don't understand
how it can be bleeding again.
올리비아는?
네 아내는?
What about OIivia? And your wife?
각자 사랑했었지
We each Ioved one of them.
난 아내를
I loved Sarah.
동생은 올리비아를...
He loved Olivia.
한 사람의 삶을
반쪽씩 나눠 살았어
We each had half of a full Iife, really,
which was enough for us.
힘들었지
Just.
여자들은 몰라도
But not for them.
좋은 마술을 하려면
희생은 필수야
See, sacrifice, Robert,
that's the price of a good trick.
넌 그걸 몰랐어
But you wouldn't know
anything about that, would you?
나도 희생을 했어
I've made sacrifices.
-No.
-Yes.
딴 사람의 마술을
훔치는 건 간단해
It takes nothing
to steal another man's work.
그렇지 않아
It takes everything.
안돼, 기다려!
나는...
No. No.
No, wait! I'm the--!
용기가 필요했지
It took courage.
매일 밤 그 기계 안에
들어가면서
It took courage to climb
into that machine every night...
죽게 될지 갈채를 받을지
...not knowing
if I'd be the man in the box...
몰랐으니까
...or in the Prestige.
그 대가가 뭐였는지
보고 싶어?
Do you wanna--?
Do you wanna see what it cost me?
직접 확인해봐
You didn't see where you are, did you?
봐, 보라구
Look. Look.
상관없어
I don't care.
미국까지 가면서
You went halfway around the world.
엄청난 돈을 썼고
You spent a fortune.
끔찍한 짓을 했어
You did terrible things.
아주 끔찍한 짓을...
Really terrible things, Robert.
하지만 헛수고였지
And all for nothing.
헛수고?
-For nothing?
-Yeah.
우리가 왜 이랬는지
모르는군
You never understood why we did this.
관객은 진실을 알아
The audience knows the truth.
세상은 단순해
The world is simple. It's miserable.
비참하고
원칙만을 따르지
Solid all the way through.
아주 잠깐이라도
그들을 속인다면
But if you could fool them,
even for a second...
궁금해하는
그들 모습에서
...then you could make them wonder.
특별한
And then you....
아주 특별한 것을 보게 돼
Then you got to see something
very special.
정말 모르겠어?
You really don't know?
감탄하는 그들의 표정!
It was-- It was the Iook on their faces.
마술은 3단계로
이뤄집니다
Every magic trick consists
of three parts or acts.
1단계는 '평범한 마술'
The first part is called the Pledge.
마술사가 뭔가를
보여주죠
The magician shows you
something ordinary.
2단계는 '대전환'
The second act is called the Turn.
마술사가
평범한 걸 가지고
The magician takes
the ordinary something...
특별한 묘기를
선보입니다
...and makes it into
something extraordinary.
박수는 이릅니다
But you wouldn 't clap yet...
사라지게 하는 걸론
부족하니까요
...because making something disappear
isn 't enough.
다시 나타나도록
만들어야 합니다
You have to bring it back.
Hey.
여러분은 비법을
Now you're looking for the secret.
알아채지 못해요
But you won 't find it because,
of course, you're not really looking.
사실, 알아내려고
하지도 않죠
알면 실망이니
You don 't really want to work it out.
속기를 원하죠
You want to be fooled.